[MUSIC]
(音乐)
Stanford University,
斯坦福大学,
>> All right, well, welcome to Stanford CS193P,
> >好吧,好吧,欢迎来到斯坦福CS193P,
Developing Applications for iOS, winter of 2017,
iOS应用程序开发,2017年冬天,
This is Lecture number 9,
这是第九讲
And today we have only one topic which is Table View,
今天我们只有一个主题表视图,
And I'm gonna go through a bunch of slides to talk about
我要穿过一群幻灯片来谈论
the concepts of it,
它的概念,
And then we're gonna have a humongous demo
然后我们会有一个巨大无比的演示
that we're gonna build a Twitter client and
我们要建立一个Twitter客户端
it's gonna use Table View and
它会使用表格视图和
some other things that we've learned, like Text Field,
其他一些我们学过的东西,像文本字段,
And Table View, what is it?
和表视图,它是什么?
You've seen a Table View in all sorts of iOS apps,
你见过各种各样的iOS应用程序表视图,
It's just this UI where there's a list of things,
只是这个UI的事情的列表,
There's really two different kinds of looks to Table View,
有两种不同的表视图看起来,
There's the kind on the left there,
有左边的那种,
which we call plain style,
我们称之为朴素的风格,
Plain style is just a list of things,
普通样式只是事情的列表,
And it might be collected into groups like little sections,
和它可能收集到团体像小部分,
But it's mostly just a big long list,
但它主要只是一大长串,
On the right side, is called a grouped style,
在右边,称为分组的风格,
Where the sections in the table,
表中的部分,
you're more obviously disconnected from each other,
你更明显的断开,
They have you know, big gaps in between,
你知道,在之间的巨大差距,
Normally the plain style we use for dynamic data,
通常我们使用的普通样式动态数据,
Data that might have any number of items in there,
数据可能有任意数量的物品,
The group style we tend to use for static data,
该组织风格我们倾向于使用静态数据,
where we know exactly what rows are gonna be in there,
我们要知道行,
and exactly what's gonna be in them,
和什么会,
So let's talk about the names of all the parts of
让我们谈论所有的部分的名称
a Table View, so that as I'm explaining all this,
表视图,这样当我解释这一切,
you'll know what the terminology is,
你会知道的术语是什么,
First we have a table header,
首先,我们有一个表标题,
That's a UIView,
这是一个UIView,
There's only one of them,
只有一个,
It sits at the very top of the table,
坐在桌子的最顶端,
This is where, as you'll see in the demo,
在这里,您将看到在演示,
you might put a search field or something that searches
你可能会把搜索字段或搜索的东西
to find what's in your table or something like that,
找到什么表之类的,
And similarly, there's a footer view,
同样的,有一个页脚视图,
Rarely see this used,
很少看到这个,
But it's just a UIView that sits at the bottom
但它只是一个UIView位于底部
And in between, there are these things called sections,
之间,都有这些东西称为部分,
of the table,
的表,
So a section is just a combination of a header and
所以只是一个标题和部分
a footer, which are usually strings, but
一个页脚,通常是字符串,但是
also could be UIViews, and then any number of rows,
也可能是ui视图,然后任意数量的行,
That's what we call a section,
这就是我们所说的部分,
So that's a section right there,
这是一个部分,
This is the section header for the two sections that I have
这是一节头的两个部分
showing in this table, right, where it says Header 0,
这个表显示,对吧,说头0,
And these are sections footers for
这些是部分的页脚
the two sections that I have,
我有两个部分,
These two sections happen to both have the same numbers of
这两个部分都有相同数量的发生
rows in each which is two but a section, one section have
行每一个都是两个,但部分,一个部分
a 100 rows, and one could have just 1, it's perfectly fine,
一个100行,可能只有1,非常好,
This right in here, we call a table cell,
在这里,我们调用一个表格单元,
C-E-L-L, cell, and it's the UIView,
C-E-L-L、细胞和UIView,
actually UITableViewCell,
实际上UITableViewCell,
it's the name of the subclass that's in there,
的是子类的名称,
And this is the thing that's gonna draw the data that's at
这是要画出的数据的
a particular row,
一个特定的行,
And we're gonna see how that works,
我们将看到这是如何工作的,
By the way, along the bottom you're seeing source code that
顺便说一下,你看到底部的源代码
kind of corresponds with these things,
符合这些东西,
Don't worry I'm gonna get back to showing you all that stuff
别担心我会回到显示你所有的东西
in later slides,
在后面的幻灯片,
So this is the naming we use to name all the parts of
这是我们使用的命名的名字所有的部分
a table view,
一个表格视图,
And this is in plain style,
这是在朴素的风格,
All the same names work in group style,
所有相同的名称在集团工作风格,
Everything just kinda looks a little different,
一切都只是看起来有点不同,
All right, still have a header, footer,
好吧,还有一个页眉,页脚,
sections, all the same,
部分,都是一样的,
Just a little different UI look,
只是有点不同的UI看,
Now, tables can have sections or not,
现在,表可以有部分,
You don't have to have any sections, so
你不需要有任何部分,
the table on the left is just a whole list of cities and
左边的表是一个整体的城市和列表
the countries they're in and just a big long list,
他们的国家在一大长串,
On the right is kind of the same kind of list but
右边是同样的列表
you can see that they're grouped into sections there by
你可以看到,他们被分成部分
country, right,
的国家,
So Japan there, Mexico, etc,
所以日本、墨西哥等
So sections are optional,
所以部分是可选的,
not optional in the case of an option, but
不是可选的一个选项,但是
sections you can have them or not, it's totally up to you,
部分你可以与否,完全取决于你的喜好,
The type of the cell, like each row, there are four
细胞的类型,像每一行,有四个
kinda pre-defined types and then there's a custom type,
有点预定义的类型,然后有一个自定义的类型,
The four pre-defined types are subtitle where you just got
这四个预定义类型是字幕你刚刚的地方
like a title and
像一个标题和
a little smaller text subtitle under it,
小文本字幕下它,
There's default which is the same except
有违约,除非是一样的
there's no little subtitle thing,
没有字幕的事情,
There's value 1 and value 2, which is just like subtitle,
值1,值2,正如副标题,
it's just that the little thing underneath is in
只是下面的小东西
a different spot, it's either blue and
不同的地方,要么是蓝色的和
to the left or it's kind of grayed off into the right but
到左边或者有点灰色的到正确的
i's just how i's laying out the basic information there,
我就是我的布局的基本信息,
Now a custom cell can have arbitrary UI
现在一个定制的细胞可以有任意的UI
in it as you will see,
正如您将看到的,
So how do we use a table view?
那么,我们如何使用表格视图?
Okay, a table view is a UIView,
好的,UIView表视图,
i's actually subclass UIScrollView because i's
我因为是子类
scrolling through all those rows,
通过所有这些行滚动,
Well 99% of the time, we use the special ViewController
99%的时间,我们使用特殊ViewController
So how do we do it?
那么我们怎么做呢?
called UITableViewController in UIKit,
叫UITableViewController UIKit,
And UITableViewController is just a convenient package to
和UITableViewController只是一个方便的包装
use UITableView in and its self,view is a UITableView,
使用UITableView及其自我,视图是一个UITableView,
Okay, so you would only use a UITableViewController
好的,那么你只会使用UITableViewController
when your entire self,view is going to be filled
当你的整个自我,视图将会填满
with a table view,
表视图,
And you can add one into your storyboard just by dragging it
你可以添加一个到你的故事板通过拖动它
out as we always do,
我们总是一样,
There's a thing called Table View Controller and
有一种东西叫做表格视图控制器
it's just gonna drag it out,
它只是要拖出来,
Now it's a controller, so when you drag it out,
现在这是一个控制器,所以当你拖出来,
it looks like an MVC,
它看起来像MVC,
But inside of that MVC,
但在MVC,
there is a table view sitting there, okay?
有一个表格视图坐在那里,好吗?
And so what you see here the controller,
所以你在这里看到的控制器,
is a UITableViewController,
是一个UITableViewController,
and the self,view of it is a UITableView,
和自我的观点UITableView,
Okay, subclass of UIScrollView,
好的,UIScrollView的子类,
Now like any other ViewController,
现在像其他ViewController一样,
if you're going to do anything with this thing,
如果你要用这个东西,做任何事
you need to subclass it, right?
你需要子类,对吧?
Just like you create a calculator view controller or
就像你视图控制器或者创建一个计算器
graph view controller,
图视图控制器,
you need to subclass, your UITableViewController as well,
你需要子类,UITableViewController,
And you do it the same way, right?
和你一样,对吧?
New files are created,
创建新文件,
It's gonna be a Cocoa Touch Class of course,
它会触控类当然,
It's gonna be a subclass of UITableViewController,
它会UITableViewController的子类,
Make sure you pick that,
确保你选择,
Don't say it's a subclass of UIViewController,
不要说这是ui的一个子类,
It has to be a subclass UITableViewController if you
它必须是一个子类UITableViewController如果你
want it to work,
想要的工作,
And then you just set it in the identity inspector
然后把它的身份检查
Just exactly like any other controllers, just that it has
就像任何其他控制器,它
to be your class,
您的课,
to be subclass UITableViewController,
UITableViewController子类,
This UITableViewController subclass
这UITableViewController子类
is also going to serve as the data source and delegates,
也将作为数据源和代表,
Okay, the data source is just a special kind of delegate for
好的,数据源是一种特殊的委托
getting the data in the table,
表中的数据,
For the table view that's inside of it,
里面的表视图,
So, we're gonna talk a lot more about that
所以,我们要更多的谈论
down the road here,
在路上,
By the way, if you right click on the view controller and
顺便说一下,如果你右键单击视图控制器
you get that black window to come up, you can actually see
黑色窗口出现,你可以看到
it, if you look down towards the bottom there,
如果你向下看向底部,
you see data source and delegate,
数据源和委托,
Their properties and they're pre wired up for you,
属性和他们之前的连接给你,
If you use this UITableViewController thing,
如果你使用这个UITableViewController的事情,
just pre-wires it up,
pre-wires它,
That the controller is the delegate and
控制器是委托
data source of the table view,
数据源的表视图,
If you don't use UITableViewController,
如果你不使用UITableViewController,
by the way, this kinda pre-packaged one?
顺便说一下,这有点预包装的吗?
Then you'll have to wire up the data source and
然后你将不得不数据源和连接
delegate, you know, either in code by saying
委托,你知道,在代码中说
tableView,delegate = self or something like that,
表视图,委托=自我之类的,
You'll have to do it yourself but 99% of the time you're
你必须自己动手,但你99%的时间
just gonna use this UITableViewController,
要使用这个UITableViewController,
Cuz usually the best UI for a table view, is for
因为通常最好的表视图,UI
it to take over the whole screen,
它接管整个屏幕,
For it to fill the whole screen, it's rare that you can
填满整个屏幕,很少
have a table view in part of your screen,
有一个表格视图在屏幕的一部分,
So you can edit the attributes of the table view itself,
所以你可以编辑表格视图本身的属性,
of course, by just clicking on it and
当然,只需点击它
bringing up the attributes inspector,
将属性检查器,
One thing that's a little frustrating about a table view
一件事有点令人沮丧的表视图
is you've got the table view cells, which are UIViews,
你有表格视图细胞,ui视图,
And then you've got the table view kind of that they're
然后你有他们的表视图类
contained in,
包含在,
That's a UIView also,
这是一个UIView也,
And then you've got the table view controller behind it,
然后你有它背后的表格视图控制器,
And you wanna set attributes on all of these things,
和你想要设置的属性在所有这些事情,
So don't forget you can do Ctrl+Shift+Left-click, and
所以不要忘记你可以按Ctrl + Shift +左击,和
it'll put up a little menu,
它会把一个小菜单,
Says, okay, what thing under the mouse do you want?
说,好吧,什么事你想要在鼠标?
Do you want the cell, the table view, or the controller?
你想要电池,表格视图,或控制器吗?
And so that'll help you dig down to the thing you want,
这将帮助你挖到你想要的东西,
All right, but once you have it selected,
好吧,但是一旦你已经选择它,
whichever one you want, like the TableView or
哪个你想要的,像TableView或
the Controller or the Cell, you can inspect it of course,
控制器或细胞,当然,你可以检查它
Now, one important thing is this grouped versus plain that
现在,这是一个重要的分组和平原
I showed you at the very beginning,
在一开始,我给你
So here I'm gonna switch this one which is plain
这里我要换这一个平原
over to grouped,
分组,
So I'm just picking grouped in the style there,
所以我选择分组的风格,
in the inspector,
在检查员,
Another important attribute is dynamic versus static,
另一个重要的属性是动态和静态的,
So dynamic is all the contents are coming from some database,
所以动态是所有的内容都来自一些数据库,
And static is, I'm gonna put all the content right here in
和静态,我要把所有的内容在这里
the story board, okay?
这个故事,好吗?
So here we'll switch this one over to static,
这里我们将这个切换到静态的,
So this is now a static, grouped table view,
这是现在一个静态,分组表视图,
And I told you that usually static table views
我告诉你,通常静态表视图
are grouped, and usually only grouped ones are static,
分组,通常只有分组是静态的,
So usually these kinda go together,
通常这些有点混合在一起,
They don't have to, they're separate properties, but
他们不需要,他们单独的属性,但是
they generally go together,
他们通常一起去,
Now the UI for these rows, most of the time you're
现在的UI这些行,你大部分的时间
just going to build by dragging UI in,
要构建通过拖放界面,
So here I'm just dragging the label in here, and you know,
这里我只是把标签拖在这里,你知道,
maybe I'll change the name of the label, dragging the UI
也许我会改变标签的名称,拖动UI
switch in there, cuz I want to set up some settings,
开关在那里,因为我要设置一些设置,
Often times, by the way, this thing is used for settings and
通常,顺便说一下,这个是用于设置和
things like that,
类似这样的事情,
And then if I want to talk to these switches and
如果我想跟这些开关和
labels that I brought in there, I'm actually gonna
标签,我带了,我真的会
create outlets to my UITableViewController,
创建媒体UITableViewController,
And since what's in this table is fixed for
因为在这张桌子是固定的
all time in the storyboard,
在故事板中,
I'm building it in a storyboard,
我是建筑在故事板,
that's perfectly fine,
这是非常好,
So I would just Ctrl + drag from them to my controller,
所以我就从他们Ctrl +拖动到控制器,
which will work, and then I can create an outlet for
这将工作,然后我可以创建一个出口
example, my feature enabled switch outlet and
我的功能开关插座和启用
it'll create an outlet here,
这将创建一个出口,
And then in my code and my controller,
然后在我的代码和控制器,
I can obviously do whatever I want to that switch,
我可以做任何我想要的开关,
So, it's almost like when you have a static table view, it's
所以,就像当你有一个静态表视图,它是
almost just like a normal view that you would build UI in,
几乎就像一个正常的视图中,您将构建UI,
It's just that it's divided into these rows,
只是它分为这些行,
Which is nice for something like settings, right?
为类似的设置很好,对吧?
If you think about the settings app, right,
如果你想设置应用程序,
on your phone,
在你的手机上,
It's got a lot of UI that's kind of in rows right, and
它有很多UI的行,和
in tables,
在表中,
So, if you really wanna see how static table view works,
所以,如果你真的想看到静态表视图是如何工作的,
get your phone out, go to the general settings app and
拿出你的手机,去应用,一般设置
just look around in there,
看看周围,
That is table view after table view after table view where
表视图的表视图后表视图
the rows are static built in some storyboard somewhere by
行是静态的一些故事板的地方建成的
Apple,
苹果,
All right, so that's pretty much it for static table,
好吧,这是几乎静态表,
These are pretty straightforward to do,
这些都是很简单的,
So I'm gonna clear this UI out of here,
所以我要清楚这个UI出去,
this featured enabled out of there, then we're gonna talk
这个特点使出来,然后我们会说话
about a different kind of table view, which is dynamic,
一种不同的表视图,这是动态的,
So a dynamic table view, you set it here by picking dynamic
所以动态表视图,选择动态设置在这里
property, prototypes, rather, there instead of static cells,
财产,原型,相反,而不是静态的细胞,
really is a totally different kind of animal, and
真的是一种完全不同的动物,
I'm gonna switch back to plain style because usually dynamic
我要切换回普通样式,因为通常是动态的
tables are plain style,
表是简单的风格,
These rows now instead of being something you're
现在这些行,而不是你的东西
gonna build the UI and
要构建UI和
they're static, instead they're prototypes,
它们是静态的,而不是他们的原型,
They're things that are gonna be copied for every row,
他们会为每一行被复制的东西,
So whatever UI you would build in one of these rows,
所以无论UI构建在这些行,
And you can build customize UI,
您可以构建定制用户界面,
like we saw with the static one,
像我们看到的静态,
It's gonna be copied for every single row,
它会被复制对于每一行,
So these are prototypes,
这是原型,
You see what I mean by prototype?
你明白我的意思的原型?
It's like a template that's gonna be copied over and
就像一个模板的复制过去,
over and over to make your table,
一遍又一遍,让你的表,
So that's a really different kind of
这是一个非常不同的
way of looking at things,
看待事物的方式,
Because this data that's gonna go into these rows is
因为这个数据是要进入这些行
coming from some database somewhere probably and
可能来自一些数据库的某个地方
filling out all this information,
填写这些信息,
So it's a little more complicated to build
这是一个有点复杂
a table like this, but not a lot more,
这样的表,但不是很多,
So you can click on any one of the cells and
你可以点击任何一个细胞
you can inspect it, right?
你可以检查它,对吧?
The prototypes that you want,
你想要的原型,
For example you could change its type from being custom
例如你可以改变它的类型被定义
to being subtitle,
副标题,
All right, so here's what a subtitle cell looks like,
好吧,这是一个副标题细胞是什么样子,
Remember I showed you in the very second slide,
记住我给你的第二张幻灯片,
it's one of the pre-canned types,
这是一个预定义的类型,
And it just has, you know,
只是,你知道,
a text field, like a little smaller text field,
一个文本字段,就像一个小文本字段,
So that's a subtitle,
这是一个副标题,
You can also set with accessory there,
你也可以设置与配件,
a little thing that can appear on the right,
一件小事,可以出现在右边,
It could be a little check mark that you turn on and off,
它可以是一个复选标记,你打开或关闭,
It could be a disclosure indicator,
它可能是一个信息披露指标,
which you want to put there if clicking on this row is going
你想把如果点击这一行吗
to segue,
继续,
Okay, that little disclosure indicator is just a little,
好吧,那个小披露指标只是一个小,
kind of gray arrow thing that lets the user know,
灰色箭头的东西,可以让用户知道,
hey if I click on this row, it's going to segue,
嘿,如果我点击这一行,它将继续,
There's also kind of a special one called detail disclosure,
还有一种特殊的一个叫详细披露,
And the detail disclosure looks like this,
和细节披露是这样的,
it's a little "i" in a circle,
这是一个小“我”在一个圆,
And what's really cool about that is you can segue by
有什么很酷,你可以继续
clicking on the row, but if you click on the little blue
单击行,但如果你点击小蓝
I, it does a different segue,
我,一个不同的segue,
Okay, so you kind of have your row doing two different
好的,所以你有做两种不同的行
segues, depending on whether they touch on the little i or
segue,取决于他们是否联系我或小
touch somewhere else,
触摸别的地方,
You see the little gray arrow next to the i?
你看到我旁边的小灰色箭头?
That's the disclosure indicator,
披露的指标,
So if I click on this row, it's going to segue,
如果我点击这一行,它将继续,
If I click on the little i,
如果我点击小,
it's gonna do some different segue,
它会做一些不同的继续,
Maybe bring up some modal panel with some information or
可能带来一些模态与一些信息或面板
something like that,
类似的,
We'll talk about how that works in a second,
我们将讨论如何在第二个工作,
All right, so I'm gonna go back to non-details,
好了,我要回到non-details,
go ahead and get rid of that thing,
去摆脱那件事,
But another style besides the four pre-canned
但另一个风格除了四个预定义
ones I talked about in the beginning of this lecture
我讲的这节课的开始
that you can pick is custom,
你可以选择自定义,
So custom means that, that's just a UIView,
所以定制意味着,这只是一个UIView,
that you can build any UI you want,
您可以构建任何你想要的用户界面,
Again similar to that feature-enabled
再一次开启了类似
with the switch that I showed,
我给的开关,
But again, this UI is going to get copied over and
但是,这个UI将被复制过去
over and over for
一遍又一遍的
Notice, by the way, there are multiple prototypes,
注意,顺便说一下,有多个原型,
That means you can have different setups of UI
这意味着你可以有不同的设置界面
that you could use for different rows, okay?
你可以使用不同的行,好吗?
And we're gonna name each of these prototypes so
我们要的名字每一个原型
that in our code, we can pick which prototype we want for
在我们的代码,我们可以挑选我们想要的原型
a certain row,
一个特定的行,
It will copy that prototype,
它将复制原型,
Now, these custom cells, you can resize them,
现在,这些定制的细胞,你可以调整它们,
You can drag stuff into them, build UI you want,
你可以拖拽东西,你想要构建UI,
Here, I've built this complicated UI with text
在这里,我已经建立了这个复杂的UI文本
fields and an image,
字段和一个图像,
This is very similar to a UI that I'm gonna build in
这非常类似于我要构建UI
All right, now when you build this UI you're gonna want
好了,现在,当你建立这个UI你会想要的
the demo,
演示,
to use proper layout,
使用适当的布局,
So stack views and hooking it to the edges just like you did
所以堆栈视图和连接到边缘就像你做的一样
with the calculator or even stuff on the inside,
计算器甚至的东西在里面,
I'll show you a little bit of that today,
我会给你一点,今天,
a little more auto layout,
自动布局,
Because if you do that, then the table view will be able to
因为如果你这样做,那么表格视图就可以
figure out the size this thing needs to be dynamically,
算出尺寸这个东西需要动态,
Okay, if you don't do the right auto layout then you
好吧,如果你不做正确的自动布局你
kind of just have to fix the height of the rows, and
只需要修复的高度的行,和
I'm going to talk about that in a minute as well,
我要谈论这个问题,
So generally you want to do auto layout properly
所以通常你想做汽车布局更合理
in there if you can,
如果你能,
Now ther's no way I could wire up these
我现在没有办法连接
elements directly to my controller,
元素直接向我的控制器,
Do you see why?
你知道为什么吗?
Because ther's only one outlet in my controller for
因为在我的控制器只有一个出口
one of these labels,
其中一个标签,
But there are hundreds of rows,
但也有数百行,
So how is my one outlet gonna?
所以是我的一个出路如何?
It can't be hooked up to 100 at once, okay,
不能连接到100,好吧,
But I still need outlets because how am I gonna
但我仍然需要媒体,因为我要如何
set these things?
设置这些东西?
All right, and so
好吧,所以
the way we're gonna deal with that is we're gonna wire these
我们要处理的是我们将线
things up to outlets in the UITableViewCell,
东西在UITableViewCell网点,
The UIView that contains them,
UIView包含,
So I told you that this cell is a UIView,
所以我告诉你,这个细胞UIView,
a UITableViewCell, and it contains all of these things,
UITableViewCell,它包含了所有的这些事情,
these labels and stuff,
这些标签和东西,
So, we're gonna have outlets in that,
所以,我们要在,
Now this is the first time you've ever seen
这是你第一次见过
outlet in anything but a controller and pretty much
插座一个控制器和差不多
this is the only other time you're gonna have outlets,
这是你唯一一次会有网点,
You can't have outlets in a regular view, but
你不能有媒体在普通视图中,但是
you can have outlets in these special table view cells,
你可以在这些特殊的表视图细胞,
All right, so let's see a little bit of how that works,
好吧,让我们看看一些这是如何工作的,
So, one thing, if you're gonna have outlets,
所以,一件事,如果你要有网点,
you know you're gonna need to have subclass, right?
你知道你会需要子类,对吧?
Just like you have a controller, you can't use
就像你有一个控制器,你不能使用
a generic UIViewController, can't put any outlets in that;
一个通用的ui,不能把任何媒体;
you have to subclass it so you can wire out, same thing here,
你必须子类可以线,这里也一样,
You're gonna have to make a custom subclass,
你需要自定义子类,
a UITableViewCell,
UITableViewCell,
You do that with New File,
你的新文件,
It is still a Cocoa Touch Class, but here you're going
这仍然是一个可可触摸类,但是在这里你会
to choose UITableViewCell as the super class,
选择UITableViewCell超类,
not UITableViewController,
不是UITableViewController,
UITableViewCell,
And again UITableViewCell is a subclass of UIView also,
再一次UITableViewCell也UIView的子类,
All right, so you're going to pick a UITableViewCell,
好吧,那么你要选择一个UITableViewCell,
by the way,
顺便说一下,
call it something like MyTableViewCell or whatever,
称之为MyTableViewCell之类的,
And then you're gonna do the exact same thing where you're
然后你会在你做同样的事情
gonna have that cell selected,
会有细胞选择,
And you're gonna go to the identity inspector,
你会去身份检查员,
And you're gonna change it from being a generic
你会改变它从一个通用的
UITableViewCell to being MyTableViewCell,
UITableViewCell MyTableViewCell,
And this is gonna allow you to create outlets
这将允许您创建
In MyTableViewCell to these things that are contained
在MyTableViewCell包含这些东西
inside MyTableViewCell,
MyTableViewCell内部,
Okay, so now we can wire them up,
好了,现在我们可以连接起来,
So remember that static elements,
所以记住,静态元素,
those things I showed you at the beginning,
在一开始,这些东西我给你
those are wired up to the controller,
这些都是连接到控制器,
Dynamic elements, where we have these prototypes,
我们有这些原型的动态元素,
those are wired up to the TableViewCell outlets,
这些都是连接到TableViewCell网点,
So what does it look like to wire them up?
所以它看起来像连接起来吗?
I'm gonna have to do the same thing with the controller
我要做同样的事情与控制器
where I'm gonna get the UI and the code on screen
在哪里我要去UI代码在屏幕上
at the same time with the assistant editor,
同时,助理编辑,
By the way, when you do that, if you're in automatic mode,
顺便说一下,当你这样做,如果你在自动模式下,
there, see where it says automatic?
,看到说自动?
It's pointing at automatic,
指着自动,
It's not going to bring up the UITableViewCell, even if you
它不会打开UITableViewCell,即使你
have the TableViewCell selected in the UI,
已经选择了TableViewCell在UI中,
It's still gonna bring up the controller, okay?
它仍然会打开控制器,对吧?
So if you want to wire up outlets to a TableViewCell,
所以如果你想连接TableViewCell网点,
you have to manually or
你必须手动或
forcibly get that TableViewCell- not
强行TableViewCell——不是
the TableViewController- TableViewCell, on this side,
表——TableViewCell,在这边,
So one way you can do it is by switching from Automatic
所以你可以做到的一种方法是通过从自动切换
to Manual and then navigating over to finding your
手册,然后导航到找到你
TableViewCell,swift class, right?
TableViewCell,斯威夫特类,对吧?
And then choosing that,
然后选择,
And now you're in manual mode,
现在你在手动模式,
you've got the TableViewCell on the right, and
你右边的TableViewCell,
you've got your storyboard on the left,
你有你的故事板在左边,
So, now you can Ctrl+drag, right?
所以,现在你可以按Ctrl +阻力,对吧?
You just need to be able to Ctrl+drag
你只需要按Ctrl +阻力
between them is the problem,
他们之间的问题,
So you gotta have them both on screen,
所以你必须有他们两个在屏幕上,
All right, so then, once I have them on screen,
好吧,那么,一旦我让他们在屏幕上,
I Ctrl+drag, just absolutely normally,
我按Ctrl +拖动,就完全正常,
And it's gonna do all the things that an outlet does,
要做所有的事情,一个出口,
it's gonna ask me, an outlet or action,
它会问我,一个出口或行动,
By the way, you can do outlet or action here,
顺便说一下,你可以做出口或动作,
And it's gonna ask,
会问,
So here, I've picked that photo, the blue thing,
这里,我选择照片,蓝色的东西,
Let's say it's a photo,
假设这是一个照片,
And I'm calling this my photoImageView,
我称之为photoImageView,
And it creates an outlet here,
这里创建了一个出口,
Okay, so that's great,
好了,这很好,
Now this TableViewCell code can talk to that photo,
现在这个TableViewCell代码可以跟这张照片,
The ImageView could for example set the image or
ImageView可以设置图像或为例
whatever,
无论如何,
But of course it needs to know what information to put
当然,它需要知道什么信息
in that photo for that row, right?
在这张照片这一行,对吧?
This thing is gonna be repeated 100 times, and
这个东西是重复100次,
each one needs to know what its row's photo is,
每一个需要知道什么是连续的照片,
So you're also gonna need some public API on your
所以你也需要一些公共API
TableViewCell which gives it the data it needs to fill up
TableViewCell给它所需要的数据填满
all its outlets,
所有的媒体,
Okay, so you're gonna have some var, which I've
好的,所以你会有一些var,这我
called infoShownByThisCell, could be of any type you want,
叫infoShownByThisCell,可能是你想要的任何类型的,
And somebody is gonna set it, you'll see soon who sets it,
有人会把它,你很快就会看到谁使它,
And once it sets it, now we can update the UI and
一旦它集,现在我们可以更新UI
put all this information into the outlets,
把所有这些信息,
Okay, so this is how the information at each row in
好吧,这是在每一行的信息
the table is going to be put into these UI elements,
表是放在这些UI元素,
You all following me so far?
到目前为止你们都跟着我?
All right, let's talk about these two protocols,
好吧,让我们来谈谈这两个协议,
the dataSource and the delegate, okay,
数据源和委托,
They're critical to making UITableView work,
他们使UITableView工作的关键,
UITableView is a class that literally cannot function
UITableView是字面上的类不能函数
without its dataSource and delegate,
没有它的数据源和委托,
It's not really like split view controller where, eh, you
这不是真的喜欢拆分视图控制器,呃,你
don't have to do anything with a delegate if you don't want,
不需要做任何委托如果你不想要,
it'll still work,
它仍然会工作,
This, you really have to do it,
你真的要做,这
Especially the dataSource,
特别是数据源,
If you don't give it a dataSource, the only
如果你不给它一个数据源,唯一
way a table view would work without its delegate and
一个表格视图的工作方式没有委托和
dataSource is if it were purely static table,
数据源是如果是纯粹的静态表,
Like the table that had the feature enabled with
像表启用该特性
the switch,
开关,
That you could deal without the dataSource,
你可以交易没有数据源,
But otherwise, if it's providing dynamic data,
但除此之外,如果它是提供动态数据,
obviously it needs the data,
显然需要大量的数据,
And the only way it can get data is
它可以得到数据的唯一方法
through its dataSource,
通过其数据源,
So, as I already told you, UITableViewController
所以,我已经告诉过你,UITableViewController
automatically sets itself as its delegate and dataSource,
自动设置本身作为其代表和数据源,
So you can just put your code for these delegate methods
所以你可以把你的代码对这些委托的方法
right in your subclass of UITableViewController, right,
在你的子类UITableViewController,
MyTableViewController, or whatever, and put it in there,
MyTableViewController等等,把它放在那里,
Also, there's a cool var in TableViewController called
此外,表中有一个很酷的var
tableView, which is basically gonna return self,view, but
表视图,这基本上是要返回自我,视图,但是
as a UITableView,
UITableView,
And that way you can talk to the UITableView that your
这样你可以跟UITableView
UITableViewController is controlling,
UITableViewController控制,
So when do we need to implement the dataSource?
所以,当我们需要实现数据源吗?
Anytime we have dynamic data, non-static,
只要我们有动态数据,非静态,
There are three really important methods in this
有三个非常重要的方法
One is, how many sections are in my table?
一是,我的表中有多少部分?
protocol,
议定书,
Could be one section if the whole thing is just
可如果整件事只是一个部分
a bunch of rows,
一群行,
How many sections, and
有多少部分,和
then how many rows are in each section?
然后在每个部分有多少行?
You're gonna be asked one by one,
你要问一个接一个地
How many rows in this section?
在这一节中有多少行?
How many rows in this section? How many are in this section?
So it knows how many rows are in every section,
所以它知道在每一节中,有多少行
And then most importantly, give me one of those
然后最重要的是,给我其中的一个
UITableViewCells to draw this row,
uitableviewcell池画这一行,
Okay, so for each row that the TableView wants to draw,
好的,所以对于TableView想画的每一行,
i's going to ask you, okay, give me a UITableViewCell now,
我问你,好吧,给我一个UITableViewCell现在,
cuz I'm going to draw this row,
因为我要画这一行,
Okay, so that's how it works,
好了,这是它是如何起作用的,
that's fundamentally how this works,
本质上这是如何工作的,
Now, all these methods are in the UITableViewDataSource
现在,所有这些方法都需要
protocol,
议定书,
So let's look at the last one, the give me a UITableViewCell,
让我们看看最后一个,给我一个UITableViewCell,
cuz it's the most complicated,
因为它是最复杂的,
The other ones are super, super simple,
其他的都是超级,超级简单,
So the way that you are going to give a UITableViewCell
所以你要给一个UITableViewCell
back to the TableView when it's time to draw a certain
回到了TableView的时候画一个确定
row is by a method being called,
行是由一个方法被调用,
Now, you might be worried here, it's like woah,
现在,你可能会担心在这里,就像哇,
I'm gonna have this big UI with all these labels and
我要与所有这些标签和这么大的UI
image views in it, and I have, what if I have 100,000 rows?
形象的观点,我有,如果我有100000行吗?
I'm going to make 100,000 views,
我要做100000的观点,
Surely that's going to be terrible performance,
无疑这将是糟糕的性能,
And in fact, that would be terrible performance, okay,
事实上,这将是糟糕的表现,好吧,
Views are not cheap,
观点是不便宜,
But no worries, because all your UITableViewCells,
但是不用担心,因为你所有的uitableviewcell池,
these UIViews that draw the rows, they're reused,
这些ui视图绘制行,他们重用,
So only the visible ones have UITableViewCells,
所以只有可见的uitableviewcell池,
As you scroll around, the ones that scroll off the top
你滚动,滚动的顶部
get picked up and put around and used on the bottom, okay?
拾起,把周围和底部使用,好吗?
And the new data keeps getting pumped into them,
新的数据不断注入,
Do you see what I'm saying?
你看到我在说什么吗?
So those cells, only the,
所以这些细胞,只有,
maybe the ones on the screen plus two or
也许那些在屏幕上加两个或两个
three on either side are actually getting created,
三两侧实际上是创建,
They're just getting reused,
他们只是得到重用,
As you scroll up and down, they keep getting reused,
当你上下滚动,他们越来越重用,
Now, the thing about that reuse,
现在,重用的事,
I want you to be very careful of,
我想要你非常小心,
I put it in red,
我把它放在红色,
When I put it in red, you know that means wake up and
当我把它放在红色,你知道这意味着醒来
watch out, cuz your homework,
小心,因为你的家庭作业,
When you're doing multithreaded things,
当你做多线程的事情,
you've got to be careful,
你要小心,
because by the time you come back from something you asked
因为你回来的时候你问的东西
to do on another thread, your cell might be reused, okay,
在另一个线程,你的细胞会被重用,好吧,
And so you've got to be prepared for that,
所以你要做好准备,
You gotta understand whether you're still the cell you
你必须明白你是否你仍然细胞
thought you were when you sent something off to go in
还以为你当你把东西送去了进去
another thread,
另一个线程,
Okay, so I'm warning you,
我警告你,
So what does this method look like that the UITableView is
所以这个方法是什么样子,UITableView
gonna send to its data source to say,
要发送给它的数据源,
give me a UITableViewCell?
给我一个UITableViewCell ?
It's called cellForRowAt indexPath,
它被称为cellForRowAt indexPath,
You see it right there,
你看到它,
That's its signature,
这是它的签名,
It really only has that one argument, indexPath,
真的只有一个参数,indexPath,
The indexPath is just a little container of
indexPath只是一个小的容器
the section and row,
部分和行
You could imagine this is even called cellForRowAt
你甚至可以想象这是叫cellForRowAt
section and row,
部分和行,
But it just puts them in one argument called
但它把它们装进一个参数
an indexPath, okay,
一个indexPath,好吧,
And then all you return is a UITableViewCell,
然后你返回是一个UITableViewCell,
And it's gonna use that UITableViewCell to draw
它会用UITableViewCell画
that row,
这一行,
So it really couldn't be a simpler API,
这实在是一个简单的API,
It's at the heart of exactly what it's asking you to do,
它的核心是问你做什么,
Now, what are you gonna do inside this method?
现在,在这个方法你要做什么?
Well, first you're going to have to get the data from your
首先,你必须要得到从你的数据
model that you want to show in that row,
你想在这一行显示模型,
Okay,
好吧,
And you can do this any way you want,
你可以做任何你想要的方式,
I have a very convenient data structure here called
我在这里有一个非常方便的数据结构
myInternalDataStructure that happens to be divided
myInternalDataStructure发生分裂
in sections and rows,
在部分和行,
So I can just index into it,
所以我可以指数,
But you might have a different data structure,
但你可能会有不同的数据结构,
But you've gotta take the section and row so
但你得把部分和行
that you know which row you're talking about, and
你知道你正在谈论哪一行,和
get the data out of your model,
获取数据的模型,
Maybe you're doing a database query,
也许你正在做一个数据库查询,
Maybe you're even doing a network query in another
也许你甚至在另一个做网络查询
thread and it's gonna return and fill this out, whatever,
线程,它会返回,并填这张表好,无论如何,
You need to figure out how to get your data,
你需要找出如何让你的数据,
Now, once you have your data, you're gonna create a cell,
现在,一旦你有了你的数据,你要创建一个细胞,
I'm gonna show you how to do that in a second,
我要告诉你怎么做,
And then you're just gonna load up that cell
然后你要负载细胞
with the data,
的数据,
So let's talk about how we create that cell and
所以让我们来谈谈我们如何创建细胞
So I'm gonna take this little piece of code, and
所以我要把这一小段代码,和
load it up,
负载,
I'm gonna keep it on screen while I go back to showing you
我要让它在屏幕上虽然我回去给你们看
what's happening in the UI here,
在UI中,发生了什么
So first let's talk about a cell that's not a custom cell,
首先让我们来谈谈一个细胞,这不是一个定制的细胞,
It's just a regular cell like subtitle,
这只是一个常规的细胞像字幕,
You see subtitle up there?
你看到字幕?
Okay, so we're gonna use this method here called
好的,所以我们要使用这个方法
dequeueReusableCell(withIdent- ifier: for: indexPath),
dequeueReusableCell withIdent(ifier - indexPath)::
And that's just gonna return us a UITableViewCell,
要返回我们UITableViewCell,
Now, again, this is a reused UITableViewCell,
现在,再一次,这是一个重用UITableViewCell,
Okay, being reused,
好吧,被重用,
now if this cell, if there's not enough been created yet,
如果这个单元格,如果没有足够的创建,
then it will create one based on your prototype,
然后它会创建一个基于你的原型,
Whatever your prototype you pick in there,
无论你的原型你选择,
And you pick which prototype with this string,
和你选的原型与这个字符串,
the identifier string
标识符的字符串
which you set in the inspector for the cell,
设置单元格的检查员,
So, it's just in there, it's called identifier,
所以,只是在那里,它被称为标识符,
the utilities inspector on the right is inspecting that cell,
右边的公用事业公司检查员检查细胞,
that top cell that says title, subtitle,
顶细胞说标题、副标题、
it's inspecting that,
这是检查,
And I'm just setting the identifier of my cell, so
我只是设置标识符我的细胞,所以
now in my code when I say, dequeueReuseableCellwithIdent-
现在在我的代码当我说,dequeueReuseableCellwithIdent -
ifier of MyCell, it's gonna make a copy of that prototype,
MyCell丰厚,它会复制的原型,
Unless there's some to be reused,
除非有一些被重用,
then it'll just reuse them,
然后它会重用他们,
But until it gets enough to reuse,
但是,直到它得到足够的重用,
it uses that prototype and
它使用原型和
just makes copies of it as necessary,
只是复制它是必要的,
Now, this is a non-custom cell, so
这是一个非定制手机,所以
the only, well there's a few fields you can set,
唯一,你可以设置有几个字段,
You can go look at the API for UITableViewCell to find out,
你可以去看看API UITableViewCell为了找到答案,
But the cell, set those two pieces of text, title and
但细胞,设置两块文本,标题和
subtitle there,
副标题,
You just, you use textlabel,text and
你,你使用textlabel,文本和
detailtextlabel,text,
detailtextlabel、文本
Those are optional, so they could be nil,
这些都是可选的,所以他们可能是零,
because if there's a custom cell, for
因为如果有一个定制的细胞,
example, it might be nil,
的例子中,它可能是零,
So anyway that's it, you just set those,
总之就是这样,你把这些,
those are just UILabels,
这些只是uilabel,
And so you just set the text, it couldn't be easier,
所以你只是设置文本,它不容易,
And that's true for
这是真的
all the pre-canned ones, you're gonna set these,
所有预定义的,你要设置这些,
There is actually, I can show it, but there's an image also,
实际上,我可以带它,但是有一个图像,
that you can set, a little image in the cell,
你可以设置,图像在细胞中,
And that's also in the pre-canned ones,
这也是在预定义的,
so you could do that as well, okay?
你可以这样做,好吗?
So that's it, that's just simple,
就是这样,这就是简单,
that's all you need to do to provide your data
这是所有您需要做的提供数据
to the TableViewCell is just dequeue one of these cells,
TableViewCell只是出列一个细胞,
Just load it up and return it, and
加载并返回它,
now the tableView will use that to draw,
现在画的表视图将使用,
But let's talk about a custom cell, so
但让我们来谈谈一个定制的细胞,所以
now I'm talking about the second row down,
现在我谈论第二行,
And look at its type,
看看它的类型,
it's custom- it's not subtitle- it's custom,
自定义——它不是副标题——这是定制的,
Little different for a custom cell,
小不同的一个定制的细胞,
You're still gonna do dequeueReusableCellwithIdenti-
你仍然要做dequeueReusableCellwithIdenti -
fier for index path, okay?
菲尔对索引路径?
But of course you're going to use a different identifier,
当然你要使用一个不同的标识符,
cuz now I'm talking about the second cell down which I'm
因为现在我谈论我第二个单元格
calling my custom cell,
叫我定制的细胞,
Now here there's no title and subtitle in that second row,
现在这里没有标题和副标题,第二行,
Presumably there's that image and
大概有这一形象
the thing under text under it and text on the side,
下的文本在它和文本,
All the things, whatever your UI switch,
所有的事情,无论你的UI开关,
whatever you built in this custom cell,
无论你在这个自定义单元格,
And all that stuff has got outlets hooked up to
和所有这些东西有插座连接
the UITableViewCell containing it, remember all that we did?
UITableViewCell包含它,还记得我们所做的吗?
So you need to just pass the data to that UITableViewCell
所以你需要将数据传递给UITableViewCell
and it's responsible for loading up all the UI,
它负责装载所有的用户界面,
Now how do you do that?
现在你怎么做呢?
First thing you need to do is take that dequeued
你需要做的第一件事就是把它列中移除
thing that came back, which is of type UITableViewCell,
回来,这是UITableViewCell类型,
And cast it with "as" to be of
,它的“作为”
the type of your subclass of UITableViewCell,
你的UITableViewCell子类的类型,
Otherwise you won't be able to call any of this API,
否则你将无法调用这些API,
Okay, so you're just gonna do, if I can let this cell equal
好的,所以你要做的,如果我可以让这个细胞相等
the dequeued thing as MyTableViewCell,
列中移除的MyTableViewCell,
Then I'm going to talk to MyTableViewCell using its API
然后我要跟MyTableViewCell使用它的API
and set, for example, infoShownByThisCell to be
并设置,例如infoShownByThisCell
the data that's app that section in row,
行数据的应用程序部分,
Okay, so to go back to the code I was showing before,
所以回到我之前展示的代码,
that info shown by the cell is that var right there,
信息显示的细胞是var,
The var that I made public in MyTableViewCell,
我在MyTableViewCell公开的var,
And then it's gonna update UI and set all of its outlets and
然后它会更新UI和所有的媒体和设置
all of that,
所有这一切,
Okay, so that's it, that how it works,
好吧,就是这样,它是如何工作的,
Those are the two cases, the kind of pre-canned one and
这两个案例中,这种预定义的和
the custom one,
自定义一个,
They're almost identical, you're still dequeuing cells,
他们几乎一模一样,你还是退出队列细胞,
you just set the data a little bit differently,
你刚刚设置的数据有点不同,
Okay, the data source also has to know how many sections and
好的,数据源,也知道有多少部分
rows,
行,
It's really simple,
这很简单,
there's a method called numberOfSections in tableView,
有一个方法叫做numberOfSections在表视图,
And that's going to return int,
会返回int,
how many sections there are,
有多少部分,
By the way that one is optional;
顺便说一下,一个是可选的;
you don't have to implement that one,
你没有实现,
If you don't, it will assume there's one section,
如果你不,假设有一个部分,
that all the rows are in this one big section,
中的所有行这一个大的部分,
The other one though, which is numberOfRowsInSection where it
不过,另一个numberOfRowsInSection它也
passes you a section number, and
你经过一段号码
you have to say how many rows are in the section,
你说有多少行部分,
That is not optional,
这不是可选的,
that is mandatory, and you must answer this question for
这是强制性的,你必须回答这个问题
every single section that you claim that your table has
每一个部分,你声称你的表
with numberOfSections in table, okay?
与numberOfSections表,好吗?
So that's it, that's simple, why does it need to know how
就是这样,很简单,为什么它需要知道
many rows and all of the sections, by the way?
许多行和所有的部分,顺便说一下吗?
Cuz it's a scroll view and it needs to know how big a thing,
因为这是一个滚动视图,它需要知道一件事,多大
it needs to set it's content size basically, right?
它需要设置它的内容大小基本上,对吧?
It needs to know how big a thing it's scrolling over, so
它需要知道多大的一件事是滚动的,所以
it needs to know,
它需要知道,
But it also needs to know when to ask you for the data and
但它也需要知道什么时候问你的数据
all that, so it's pretty obvious it needs to know that,
这一切,所以很明显需要知道,
In a static table by the way,
在静态表,
it's not gonna ask you these questions,
不会问你这些问题,
So don't even worry about that,
所以不担心,
The static table is fixed in the StoryBoard, so
在故事板静态表是固定的,所以
it's never asking you for the data,
它从来没有问你的数据,
So it's never gonna ask you how many rows and sections and
所以是不会问你多少行和部分
all that stuff there is,
所有这些,
So the summary is you set the tableView's data source,
总结是你设置视图的数据来源,
That's automatic if you're using UITableViewController,
如果你使用UITableViewController自动,
You implement numberOfSections and numberOfRowsInSection,
你实现numberOfSections numberOfRowsInSection,也
And then you implement cellForRowAt,
然后你实现cellForRowAt,
And give back a tableView cell,
和回馈表视图单元,
either a custom subclass if you're doing custom,
如果你做定制的自定义子类,
or just setting the detailed text label and
或者只是设置详细的文本标签和
then the normal text label if you're not, question?
然后如果你不是正常的文本标签,有问题吗?
Okay, so the question is, what do I answer for
好了,问题是,我回答
that number of sections thing if, over time,
这一数字的部分,如果随着时间的推移,
my tableView is growing, right?
我的表视图正在增长,对吧?
Maybe data is coming in from the network, or
数据来自网络,或
the user is clicking on things that makes more table happen,
用户点击更表发生的事情,
You can answer it that differently in any time, but
你可以回答它在任何时间不同,但是
what you're basically saying is, what if my model changes?
基本上你说的是什么,如果我的模型变化?
I need my UI, right, to keep up with it,
我需要我的UI,跟上,
If my model gets bigger, then I need more rows,
如果我的模型变大,那么我需要更多的行,
Well, you're gonna see that it's really important to,
好吧,你会看到它是非常重要的,
every time your model changes,
每次你的模型的变化,
you need to tell the tableView about it,
你需要告诉tableView,
And you're gonna tell it things like
你会告诉它的东西
I've added a new section,
我添加了一个新的部分,
And then it will come back and
然后它会回来
ask you all these questions again, all right,
再次问你这些问题,
So, that's how it works,
这是它是如何起作用的,
It might come back and ask you these questions including
它可能包括回来问你这些问题
cellForRowAt over and over and over,
cellForRowAt一遍又一遍,
As you tell it that you've changed your model,
当你告诉你已经改变你的模型,
But of course, your model can change over time,
当然,您的模型可以改变随着时间的推移,
By the way, the titles of the sections,
顺便说一下,标题的部分,
remember when I showed you the countries and it had Japan and
还记得我给你们的国家和日本
Mexico as titles,
墨西哥的头衔,
Those are considered part of the data,
那些被认为是数据的一部分,
So, those are part of the UITableViewDataSource
所以,这些都是需要显示的一部分
protocol as well,
协议,
This method title for header or footer in section, and
这种方法标题页眉或页脚的节
you pass the section number and it gives you the thing,
你通过节号,它给你的东西,
You can also do it with a view, using the delegate,
你也可以用一个视图,使用委托,
But if you want to just do it as a string,
但如果你想做它作为一个字符串,
you'd use the data source,
你会使用的数据源,
There's a lot of other methods in the protocol,
还有很多其他方法的协议,
I'm not gonna really talk about them,
我不会谈论他们,
they have to do with things like deleting rows or
他们与删除行或之类的东西
rearranging the rows, things like that,
重新安排行,类似这样的事情,
If your model allows those things to happen,
如果你的模型允许这些事情发生,
like things being deleted,
像被删除,
Then you're gonna have to teach yourself this,
然后你要自学,
Most of you will probably end up doing this for
你们中的大多数最终很可能会这样做
your final project,
你最后的项目,
I'm not gonna ask you to do it in the homework, but
我不会要求你去做作业,但是
you'll probably do it for your final project,
你可能会做你的最后一个项目,
It's extra credit in the homework,
额外的学分在作业,
if you wanna get a head start on that,
如果你想要在,
All right let's talk about seguing from a row,
好吧让我们谈谈哪一行,
So I've got a row there, okay,
所以我有一个行,好的,
this one actually has a detail disclosure in there as well,
这一个有一个细节披露,
And I wanna segue out of that thing, how do I do that?
我想继续那件事,我该怎么做?
Very simple,
很简单,
I do it just like any other segueing from the button,
我就像任何其他segue的按钮,
I'm just gonna Ctrl+drag from the row to the MVC I want to
我要按Ctrl +拖行到MVC我想
segue to,
跟着你,
And it's going to put up this black window,
这是要把这个黑色的窗口,
Now, this black window
现在,这个黑色的窗口
is a little different than other segues,
比其他segue有点不同,
Because you see it has two sections, Selection Segue and
因为你看到它有两个部分,选择Segue和
Accessory Action, okay?
辅助动作,好吗?
So the Selection Segue is if they click on the row and
所以选择Segue如果他们点击行和
the Accessory Action is if they click on
如果他们点击辅助动作
the little accessory button,
小附件按钮,
But it's just a normal segue, once you create the segue,
但这只是一个正常segue,一旦你创建segue,
you can click on it and inspect it,
你可以点击它,检查它,
Just like any other segue,
就像任何其他segue,
you can set its identifier up there to something,
你可以设置它的标识符,
And then you're gonna have prepare for segue,
然后你要准备segue,
So, here I've set the identifier to be AbcSegue,
所以,在这里我AbcSegue设置标识符,
So lets take a look at what prepare for
我们看看准备
segue looks like when you're doing this kinda segue,
segue看起来就像当你这样做有点segue,
It looks almost exactly the same,
看起来几乎完全一样,
here I've got a prepare for segue,
在这里我有一个准备segue,
I've noticed that the sender there is Any,
我注意到发送方有任何,
And when you're segueing into tableView,
当你segue表视图,
what do you think that Any is gonna be?
你认为是吗?
UITableViewCell, okay, that view that contains the row,
UITableViewCell,包含行,这一观点
So that is going to be the sender,
这是发送者,
Just like a button is the sender
就像一个按钮是发送方的
if you click on a button to segue, the row,
如果你点击一个按钮来segue,行,
the UITableViewCell, is the sender in that case,
UITableViewCell,发送方在这种情况下,
So the first thing you're gonna wanna
所以你要想的第一件事
do is convert the sender to a TableViewCell,
做的是把发送方TableViewCell,
And specifically to your subclass or table view cell,
特别是你的子类或表视图单元格,
If you have a custom cell in case you wanna
如果你有一个定制的细胞,以防你想
do anything that's specific to your TableView cell,
做任何特定于您的表视图单元格,
If not then you can just do it to UITableViewCell,
如果不是那么你可以做到UITableViewCell,
And then you wanna get the index path of that cell so
然后你想要得到的索引路径细胞
that you know what row where you're segueing from,
你知道行你segue是从哪里来的,
Because every row, you can click on it, it will segue,
因为每一行,你可以点击它,它会继续,
So, you need to know which row,
所以,你需要知道哪一行,
And you do that by
你这样做
And you can't pass any to that, you have to pass
你不能通过任何,你必须通过
UITableViewCell or subclass thereof, indexPath(for: cell),
UITableViewCell或子类,indexPath(:细胞),
Now, I'm gonna give you one of those index path
现在,我要给你一个索引路径
things remember?
的事情还记得吗?
and row,
行,
Then, you're gonna get your seguedToMVC as usual,
然后,你会得到你seguedToMVC像往常一样,
And you're going to prepare your Segue to public API, and
你要准备你Segue公共API,和
you're going to do it using the data in your model based
你要在模型中使用的数据
on the section and row that was clicked on,
在点击的部分和行,
Got it?
明白了吗?
So pretty easy segue from it,
所以很容易segue,
So yes you're gonna use your public API of your
是的你要使用你的公共API
segue to MVC,
MVC跟着你,
What about the table view's delegate?
表视图的代表呢?
We talked about the data
我们讨论了数据
source; what about the table view's delegate?
源;表视图的代表呢?
It's got a kind of a miscellaneous
它有一种杂项
bunch of stuff in there but generally the delegate
很多东西但一般委托
is talking about how the table view is displayed, and
在谈论如何显示表格视图,然后呢
the data source is what data is actually in the table,
数据源是数据表中,
Okay so that's the difference,
好,这就是区别,
So the delegate we're talking about things,
所以委托我们谈论的事情,
yeah they're usually the same object,
是的他们通常是相同的对象,
So the delegate also has all the will, did, should things,
所以委托也,,应该的事情,
That you could watch what's happening in the table view,
你可以在表格视图,看发生了什么
This row did get selected, things like that,
这一行做了选择,类似这样的事情,
For example, here's table view target action, so
举例来说,这里的表视图的目标行动
if when you click on a row, if you don't want a segue, but
如果当你点击一行,如果你不想继续,但
you just want to be target action like a button,
你只是想成为目标动作像一个按钮,
well you can't really do that,
你不能这样做,
You can't do target action because a row is not
你不能做目标行动,因为行不
a UIButton,
UIButton a,
But you can implement this delegate method tableView
但你可以实现tableView这个委托方法
didSelectRowAt indexPath,
And when someone touches on that row,
当有人涉及这一行,
this is gonna get called,
这是会被调用,
So, it's just like target action right,
所以,就像目标动作正确,
It told you what happened,
它告诉你发生了什么事,
So, now you can look at the index path row in section to
所以,现在你可以看看索引路径行部分
know which row was selected so we call that target action,
知道哪一行被选中我们称之为目标动作,
You did the same thing with that detail
你也做了同样的事情的细节
disclosure by the way,
信息披露的方式,
So I'm gonna click on the detail disclosure we're gonna
所以我要点击详细披露我们会
get this method in your delegate called
调用这个方法在你的委托
accessoryButtonTappedForRow- With indexPath,
与indexPath accessoryButtonTappedForRow -,
Okay, so now you know which row is that,
好的,现在你知道这行,
So when things are clicked on, you can use segue or
所以,当点击,您可以使用segue或
you can use these to find out things were clicked on and
您可以使用这些被点击,找到东西
do whatever you want,
做任何你想要的,
So yeah, a lot of wills and dids and all those things,
是的,很多遗嘱和做所有这些事情,
You can look at the documentation for
你可以查看的文档
UITableViewDelegate,
Now back to what this guy was asking before,
现在回到之前这家伙问什么,
What happens if my model changes?
如果我的模型变化?
It gets bigger?
它变大吗?
Or even gets smaller or whatever?
甚至变小什么的?
One thing you can do that's kind of a hammer is
一件事你可以做的锤子
reloadData,
If you go reloadData on your table view it's going to call
如果你去reloadData表视图的电话
all of your data source methods again,
你所有的数据源的方法,
How many sections you got, how many rows in each section?
你有多少部分,每个部分有多少行?
Give me a cell for every single visible row,
给我一个细胞对于每一个可见的行,
You see what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗?
It's going to do the whole thing all over again,
这是要做整件事都一遍又一遍,
It's kind of a hammer because if you know that you only
这是一种锤,因为如果你只知道你
changed one section okay?
改变一段好吗?
Then you can call something like reloadRows (at
然后你可以叫类似reloadRows(
indexPaths,,,),
And indexPaths would tell the sections and rows,
indexPaths告诉部分和行,
With some animation,
一些动画,
And animations can be like fade in or
可以像淡入或和动画
slide from the bottom or things like that,
从底部幻灯片或类似的东西,
So there are lighter weight ones you can call,
所以有较轻的重量,你可以叫
And I'm actually gonna show you in the demo,
我将给你演示,
we're gonna call one where we're just gonna tell
我们会打电话给一个我们要告诉
the table view that we inserted a section and
我们插入一段的表视图
it's going to immediately just ask me
它会立即就问我
the data source message about that section and nothing else,
数据源信息部分,没有别的,
So you do need to tell the table view
所以你需要告诉表格视图
every time you change your model,
每次你改变你的模型,
If you change your model in
如果你改变你的模型
any way that would change the number of sections and rows,
任何方式,改变部分和行数,
Or even the display of a row,
甚至一行显示,
you need to tell the table view,
你需要告诉表视图,
So, just always think about that when you're
所以,当你总是思考
writing table view code,
写表格视图代码,
Change my model, tell the table view,
改变我的模型,表视图,
Right away,
马上,
You want to tell the table view right away,
你想马上告诉表视图,
And change your model first, then change your table view,
首先,改变您的模型,然后改变你的表视图,
Because when you tell your table view
因为当你告诉你的表格视图
things have changed, it's gonna go back and ask you, so
事情已经发生了变化,它会回去问你,所以
for IndexPath, number of sections,
IndexPath,数量的部分,
it'll ask you those questions, some of them again,
它会问你这些问题,他们中的一些人,
So make sure your models are already changed and
已经改变了,所以确保你的模型
ready to answer those questions,
准备好回答这些问题,
Le's talk about the height of rows,
勒的谈论的行高,
The height of the row
这一行的高度
generally set in the Storyboard,
一般设置在故事板中,
So you could resize it and set it and tha's what it is but
所以你可以调整它并设置它,那是它是什么
you can also ask the delegate,
你也可以问委托,
You can also implement a method in the delegate and
你也可以委托和实现方法
it'll ask the delegate, what height should this row be?
它会问委托,身高这一行应该是什么?
This might be very useful in your homework, by the way,
这可能是非常有用的在你的家庭作业,顺便说一下,
But this is for when you have
但这是当你有
the rows that change height in some calculated way,
行改变高度在某些计算方法,
Maybe you have an image in there, and
也许你有一个图像
it's got different aspect ratios, for example,
它有不同的纵横比,例如,
And so it's different heights sometimes, whatever,
所以有时不同高度,无论如何,
So you can answer it this way,
你可以这样回答,
Of course, the other way you can control the height
当然,你可以控制高度
is by doing auto layout, and
通过自动布局,
setting your height to be automatic dimension,
设置你的身高自动维度,
If you set your height to be UITableViewAutomaticDimension,
如果你设置你的身高UITableViewAutomaticDimension,
that means go figure it out from the auto layout please,
这意味着从自动布局请去弄明白,
So those are the three was you can set the height,
这是三个你可以设置高度,
Set it fixed in the story board, answer this delegate
把它固定在故事板,回答这个委托
method here, heightForRowAt indexPath,
方法在这里,heightForRowAt indexPath,
or set it to the automatic dimension,
或者将其设置为自动维度,
If you do the automatic ways then you also probably want to
如果你自动那么你也可能想方法
set the estimated row height,
估计的行高,
That just tells the table view calculate from auto layout but
这只是告诉表格视图计算从自动布局
for all those cells the 100,000 cells that aren't
所有这些细胞没有的100000个细胞
on screen please don't do auto layout for 100,000 cells,
在屏幕上请不要做自动布局100000个细胞,
Just estimate them to be about this and as they start to come
估计他们是这当他们开始
on screen then it's gonna do the auto layout and
在屏幕上就会自动布局和
pick the exact right height okay,
选择的合适的高度好,
So that's why you need to estimate,
这就是为什么你需要估计,
And there's also a delicate method,
还有一个微妙的方法,
estimated height per row at whatever,
估计高度每一行,
So there's dozens of methods also, in table view itself,
也有很多方法,在表视图,
Not in its delegates, but in table view itself,
不代表,但在表视图本身,
You can scroll to a row cuz it's a scroll view,
你可以滚动到一行因为滚动视图,
It knows how to do scrolling,
它知道如何做滚动,
You can control the look, the separators between rows,
你可以控制看,行之间的分隔符,
All those kind of things,
所有这些事情,
So you're definitely want to familiarize yourself
所以你一定要熟悉
with the table view API itself,
表格视图API本身,
Don't forget about that,
不要忘记,
All right, so I'm not coming back to this slide,
好了,所以我不回到这张幻灯片,
So just give you a quick coming up here,
只是给你一个快速的到来,
We have collection view on Friday,
我们周五集合视图,
So collection view is very similar to table view,
集合视图非常类似于表视图,
but the layout doesn't have to be in a strict table,
但布局并不必须在严格的表,
It can be kind of laid out any way you want,
它可以提出任何你想要的方式,
But it's the same kind of thing where there's data and
但同样的事情,那里的数据和
it's gonna ask you how many sections there, how many row,
它会问你有多少部分,有多少行,
not rows but items in that section, then it's gonna have
而不是行项目部分,那么它会
this little extra mechanism for doing a lay out,
这个小额外的机制做了布置,
So it's really awesome,
这真是太棒了,
I'd love to have time to teach it in lecture not in
我想有时间教它在课堂上不是
the optional section but I've got so much to teach in this
可选的部分,但我有这么多教
course and you really need to understand TableView first,
课程,你真的需要了解TableView第一,
which is a little simpler, before you can move onto
之前有点简单,你可以继续
CollectionView- but really don't miss Friday,
周五CollectionView——但是真的不要错过,
It will be a good way to really it much more powerful
这将是一个真正的好方法更强大
kind of data presentation UI,
数据显示界面,
And then next week we gonna talk about Core Data,
然后下周我们将谈论核心数据,
which is the object-oriented database in iOS,
这是iOS的面向对象的数据库,
really powerful mechanism,
非常强大的机制,
Right now, I'm gonna be doing a big demo that shows
现在,我要做一个演示程序,展示了
how to do all this TableView stuff and
这一切TableView东西,怎么做呢
also TextField and some other things,
也TextField和一些其他的事情,
And your Assignment 4 is out,
和你的任务4,
and it's due in one week, on Wednesday and it's
它将在一个星期,周三的
basically to take what I do today and build a better one,
今天基本上采取我所做的,建立一个更好的,
More feature-full,
更feature-full,
So that's why you
这就是为什么你
always want to understand what I'm doing in lecture, because
总是想明白我在演讲,因为
I'm almost always just asking you to do the same thing,
我几乎总是要求你做同样的事情,
Okay so I'm gonna build a completely
好的,我要建立一个完全
fresh app from scratch,
新的应用程序从头开始,
Like I said before it's gonna be a Twitter client,
就像我之前说的它会是一个Twitter客户端,
We're gonna be doing Twitter searches,
我们要做的Twitter搜索,
It's gonna be a single view app,
它会单一视图应用程序,
i'm gonna call it Smashtag, kind of like hashtag,
我要叫它Smashtag,有点像标签,
As always,
像往常一样,
This is gonna be an iPhone-only app,
这是一个专用的应用程序,
And that's true for your homework as well,
这是对你的家庭作业,
Okay, iPhone-only, we're not gonna do an iPad thing,
专用的,我们不会做iPad的事情,
You already learned that with assignment three,
你已经知道与分配三个,
Trying to keep what you're learning
试图让你学习
as new as possible with each one,
与每一个尽可能新,
I'm gonna put this where I always put everything,
我要把这个我总是把一切的地方,
Here we go, I'm gonna get rid of some of these things over
好了,我要摆脱这些事情
here that we don't really use very much,
在这里,我们并不真正使用,
Actually I'm gonna leave plist as you'll see,
实际上我要离开plist您将看到,
New group, we'll do Supporting Files here, and
新组,我们会支持文件,
I will move that down,
我将下来,
Now I'm gonna start by taking my Storyboard here and
现在我要先把我的故事板
just totally wiping it out,
完全抹去,
Okay, I'm just gonna take the one controller that I got,
好了,我要带我的一个控制器,
the free one, and just delete it,
自由,就删除它,
I'm even gonna go over to this code right here and
我甚至会去这里的代码
delete that, same thing I did in the last demo,
删除,我过去做的演示,
Cuz I don't need any of that,
因为我不需要任何,
I'm gonna start from scratch here,
我要从头开始,
So, we're building a table view app, so
所以,我们正在构建一个表格视图应用程序,所以
let's grab a table view, I'm gonna scroll down here,
让我们抓住一个表格视图,我要在这里向下滚动,
Here's a table view right here, I just drag it out,
这里有一个表格视图,我只是拖出来,
Now this table view if we wanna use it as a delegate and
现在这个表格视图作为代表,如果我们想使用它
data source, or if we wanna have outlets to it, we,
数据源,或者如果我们想有网点,我们
of course, need a subclass of it,
当然,需要一个子类,
So let's go ahead and do that, New > File, okay,
让我们继续这样做,新的>文件,好吧,
It's gonna be a Cocoa Touch subclass,
它会是一个可可触摸子类,
namely a UITableViewController,
即UITableViewController,
And I'm gonna call this my TweetTableViewController,
我将称之为TweetTableViewController,
because it's gonna show tweets,
因为它会显示微博,
All right, and I'm gonna be very careful to put it here,
好吧,我要非常小心地把它放在这里,
not at the top level of my project there,
不是我的项目的顶层,
And here we go, here's our code right here,
在这里,我们走,这是我们的代码,
I'm gonna delete this View Controller Lifecycle
我要删除这个视图控制器生命周期
stuff, as usual,
的东西,像往常一样,
But you'll notice the TableViewController
但是你会注意到表
also has some extra stuff,
也有一些额外的东西,
You recognize those methods, numberOfSections, okay,
你认识这些方法,numberOfSections,好吧,
numberOfRowsInSection, and cellForRowAt indexPath,
numberOfRowsInSection,也和cellForRowAt indexPath,
These are the key UITableViewDataSource
这些都是需要显示的关键
methods here,
方法在这里,
Now there's some other UITableViewDataSource
现在有其他的需要
methods here as well, these are for
方法在这里,这些都是
things like deleting rows, moving rows,
删除行、行移动,
So when you're doing your extra credit, or
所以当你做额外的信贷,或
when you're doing your final project,
当你在做你的最后一个项目,
you'll be wanting to not delete those,
你会想要删除这些,
But I will delete those just to make our code a little bit
但我将删除那些只是为了让我们的代码
cleaner here,
清洁,
So that's our UITableViewController
这就是我们UITableViewController
subclass, we'll have to implement these in a second,
子类,我们必须实现这些,
But let's go back to our Storyboard,
但让我们回到我们的故事板,
We also obviously wanna set our identity here to instead
显然我们还想套我们的身份来代替
of being just generic UITableViewController,
仅仅是通用UITableViewController,
we want it to be a TweetTableViewController,
我们希望它是一个TweetTableViewController,
Also, where's our arrow coming in?
同时,我们的箭头来在哪里?
There's no arrow, so let's select it again and
没有箭头,让我们再次选择它,
go back to attributes and pick is initial view controller, so
回到属性和选择初始视图控制器,所以
we get this arrow coming in,
我们得到这个箭头,
Okay, otherwise, when we launch our app,
好吧,否则,当我们启动应用程序,
it's not gonna know what MVC to start with, all right?
它不会知道MVC开始,好吗?
Now whenever we have a new MVC,
现在每当我们有一个新的MVC,
what's one of the first things we always wanna do?
的第一件事是什么,我们总是想做什么?
Define its model,
定义它的模型,
Understand what this MVC is all about,
了解这MVC,
What does it show or do?
它显示或做什么?
And I'm going to pick my model to be an array of tweets,
我要选择我的模型是一个tweet数组,
Okay, I'm gonna call it tweets,
好的,我会叫它微博,
But I'm actually gonna make it be an array
但我要让它成为一个数组
of array of tweets,
阵列的微博,
Okay, why am I making an array of an array of tweets?
好的,我为什么让一个数组的数组的推文?
Because I'm going to be able to put some tweets in my table
因为我能放一些推在我的桌子上
and then go fetch some more and put more in,
然后去获取更多的投入更多,
And every time I put more in, I'm gonna put it as a new
每次我把更多的,我要把它作为一个新的
section, okay, table view section,
节,表视图部分,
So each array on the inside of this array
所以每个数组的内部数组
is another batch of tweets,
是另一批微博,
And the outer array is all of my sections,
外层数组是我所有的部分,
So I have a really nice data structure here,
所以我在这里有一个很好的数据结构,
It really matches up nicely with table view,
它与表格视图匹配很好,
And it's kind of nice to have that kind of data structure,
和这是一种很高兴这样的数据结构,
And I kind of recommend that in the homework if you can
我建议,如果你能在作业
make your data structure match up with sections and
让你的数据结构和匹配部分
rows, then it makes the implementation
行,然后实现
of all these methods down here a lot simpler,
所有的这些方法简单得多,
All right, so, I've got another part of my model,
好吧,那么,我有另一个我的模型的一部分,
though, which is some searchText,
不过,这是一些searchText,
So the searchText is like #stanford,
所以searchText就像#斯坦福大学,
that's what I wanna search for,
这就是我想要寻找,
So this searchText is what I'm searching for
这searchText就是我寻找
to find my tweets,
找到我的微博,
And I'm making this one public,
我公开这一个,
this is gonna be a public part of my model,
这是一个公共的一部分我的模型,
So anyone using my MVC, they set the search text,
所以有人使用我的MVC,他们设置搜索文本,
I will show those tweets,
我将展示这些推文,
That's what I do,
这是我做的,
All right, and I'm gonna do that by populating this part
好的,我要做的,通过填充这部分
of my model over here to show them,
我的模型在这里给他们,
So what do I need to do if the searchText is set?
所以我需要做什么如果searchText设置?
So I need to do some didSet here, so the public model,
所以我需要做一些didSet,所以公共模型,
if something sets it, I have to react well to it,
如果有什么东西使它,我必须反应良好,
I mean, one thing that I'm gonna wanna do is remove
我的意思是,我要想做的一件事是删除
all the tweets that are already in my table,
已经在我的表,所有的微博
And when I remove those from my model up here,
当我把这些从我的模型,
I need to tell the table view about it,
我需要告诉表视图,
So I'm gonna have the tableView,reloadData(), which
所以我要有tableView,reloadData(),
is the hammer, which is okay, because I removed everything,
锤子,这是好的,因为我删除一切,
so the hammer's gonna be pretty light,
所以锤子会很轻,
a little ball-peen hammer,
一个小榔头,
Okay, just going to clear the table out, so
好了,要收拾桌子了
tha's perfectly fine in this case,
在这种情况下,那是非常好的
What else do I need to do?
我需要做什么?
Well, I, now I need to search for tweets,
好吧,我,我现在需要寻找微博,
So I have to write a function to do that to search for
所以我要写一个函数来搜索
some tweet,
一些推特,
I'm also gonna set my title equal to the searchText,
我也会把我标题等于searchText
That way if I happen to be in a navigation controller or
这样如果我碰巧在导航控制器或
something like that, it'll show whatever I'm searching
这样,它会显示无论我搜索
for, #stanford or whatever at the top, so
#斯坦福之类的顶部,所以
I'll just make my UI look nice there,
我会使我的UI看起来不错,
All right, so
好吧,那么
we got to do this private func searchForTweets,
我们要做这个私人func searchForTweets,
Okay, so this is the thing that needs to go off and
这是需要去和
find these tweets, and so we'll do that in a moment,
找到这些tweet,我们会这样做,
One thing I'm also gonna do is I'm gonna do viewDidLoad,
我还要做的一件事就是我要做viewDidLoad,
just for testing purposes,
只是为了测试目的,
You notice I do this a lot when I'm developing, and
你注意到我这样做当我发展,和
I wanna have some testing,
我想有一些测试,
I'm gonna just set my model to something,
我要把我的模型,
So we'll do #stanford, okay, just for testing,
所以我们要做#斯坦福大学,好的,只是为了测试,
Once we're got our MVC working,
一旦我们得到了MVC的工作,
its public API is working, then we will remove this code,
它的公共API是工作,那么我们将删除这段代码,
It's just testing code,
这只是测试代码,
Okay, now, we have an error here,
好的,现在,我们这里有一个错误,
And this error is Swift saying excuse me,
这个错误是斯威夫特说对不起,
What is tweet?
推特是什么?
What is that type?
那是什么类型?
And I didn't really want you to be wasting your time in
我真的不希望你浪费你的时间
your homework figuring out how to go fetch
你的作业如何去获取
a tweet from Twitter and do a request and all that,
推特公司的一条微博,做一个请求,
So I wrote a framework that did it for you,
所以我写了一个框架,为你做的,
And by framework, I mean a framework like this,
框架,我的意思是这样的一个框架,
Like UIKit, right, UIKit is this like library of a whole
像UIKit,正确,这是UIKit像图书馆的一个整体
bunch of data structures that you can use to build your app,
堆数据结构,您可以使用它们来构建您的应用程序,
Well, I wrote one for you that will do Twitter stuff for it,
好吧,我为你写了一个Twitter会做东西,
And it has something in it called tweet,
和它叫微博,
And it also has something called request that lets
和它也有所谓的请求,允许
you make a Twitter request,
你让一个Twitter的请求,
All right, so that thing is right over here,
好了,这东西在这里,
Now, how do frameworks work?
现在,框架如何工作?
How do you use them when they're not built into
你如何使用它们时不内置
the system like Apple?
系统像苹果?
And the answer is, you need to build a higher level structure
答案是,您需要构建一个更高层次的结构
for Xcode to work with called a workspace,
在Xcode使用称为工作区,
So I'm actually gonna close this project,
所以我真的要关闭这个项目,
I'm closing this project,
我关闭这个项目,
And I'm going to Xcode, and I'm gonna create a new thing,
我要Xcode,我要创建一个新的东西,
which you've never seen before, called a workspace,
你从未见过的,称为工作区,
Now when I create this workspace,
现在当我创建工作区,
it wants to know where to put it,
它想知道把它放在哪里,
Be careful here, look,
小心这里,看,
it's trying to put it inside my Smashtag project,
它试图把在我Smashtag项目,
which I don't wanna do that,
我不想这样做,
I wanna put it up the top of my Developer level here,
我想把它放在我的开发人员水平的顶部,
same place I put all of my projects, okay,
同一个地方我把我所有的项目,好吧,
so really be careful about that,
所以很小心,
So I'm gonna call this L9, this is lecture 9, so
所以我要称之为L9,这是讲座9,所以
we'll call it L9,
我们叫它L9,
And I hit Save, and this created this workspace,
我点击保存,这个创建工作区,
But notice in the navigator, there's nothing there,
但要注意在navigator,什么也没有,
So what do we put in a workspace?
我们将在一个工作区吗?
Well, what we put in a workspace are other projects,
好吧,我们将在一个工作区中其他项目,
And this workspace is just gonna collect all those
这个空间是要收集所有这些
projects, because they kind of go together,
项目,因为他们一起去,
And obviously, this Twitter framework that I'm providing
很明显,这个Twitter框架,我提供
to you right here goes together with Smashtag,
你在这里Smashtag一起,
which is this thing we've been working on so far,
这是我们一直在做这件事到目前为止,
Now what you drag down in here is the ,xcodeproj,
现在你在这里是拖累,xcodeproj,
because it's the project itself that you wanna put in
因为它是项目本身,你想
this workspace,
这个工作空间,
So you just drag that in for both of them, so
所以你就拖,他们两人,
I'm gonna open this one as well,
我要打开这一个,
Here's the Xcode project for this Twitter thing,
这是Twitter的Xcode项目的事情,
Drag in, now be careful not to put it inside,
现在拖,小心不要把它里面,
see how that's trying to put it inside Smashtag there?
看看这是试图把它放进Smashtag吗?
Put it outside, so that they're siblings,
外,他们的兄弟姐妹,
Now I have this workspace right here that has two
现在我有两个这里的工作区
projects in it, and you even go here and hide others,
项目,你甚至去这里和隐藏,
And if we look in the Smashtag one, woo, looks familiar,
如果我们Smashtag一看,哇,看起来很熟悉,
This is the code we were just working on, right?
这是我们的代码只是工作,对吧?
If we look in the Twitter one,
如果我们在推特上,
this is the code I am providing you,
这是我给你的代码,
Now, what's in here?
现在,在这里是什么?
Here's tweet which is this struct and
这是这个结构体和微博
it's got all the things you would expect in a tweet,
它有所有你期望在一条微博,
The text of the tweet, the user who created it,
推特的文本,创建它的用户,
which is another thing, user right here,
这是另一件事,这里的用户,
and the user has a screen name that's at sign something,
和用户有一个屏幕名称的标志,
the actual name, a unique identifier for the user,
实际的名称,用户的惟一标识符,
Back to tweet, it's also got a unique identifier,
回推,它也有一个惟一的标识符,
It's also got things that are embedded in the tweet like
也有东西嵌在推特
other hashtags and
其他标签和
other users that are referenced inside the tweet,
引用的其他用户在推特,
And even media cuz you know a lot of times
甚至媒体因为你知道很多次了
tweets have an image with them too,
微博也有一个图像与他们,
And the other thing that's of importance in this Twitter
和另一件事的重要性的Twitter
framework that I'm giving you is this class Request,
框架,我给你的是这个类的请求,
Twitter Request right here,
Twitter的请求,
And this Request class is the thing you use to make requests
和这个请求类是您使用请求
for Twitter,
的推特上
Now, you don't need to look at any of the implementation
现在,你不需要看任何的实现
of any of this, and in fact, you can go and
的,事实上,你可以去
do assistant editor,
做助理编辑,
And if you do assistant editor on something like this,
如果你在这样的助理编辑,
you're actually gonna see its public API here,
你会看到它的公共API,
See all those public, public public, public,
看到所有这些公众,公众公开,公开的,
public; now we have not seen this public keyword before,
公众;现在我们还没有见过这个公共关键字,
all we've seen is private or fileprivate,
我们所看到的是私人或fileprivate,
So what does this public thing mean?
所以这个公共的事情是什么意思?
Look, I put public in all this these things over here,
看,我把在这里的这些东西,
Public means that not only is it not private but
公共意味着不仅不是私人
you can see it even if this framework is being used by
你可以看到它,即使这个框架被
some other project,
一些其他的项目,
So public means public outside of this framework, right,
所以公共意味着公共这个框架之外的,对吧,
make sense?
有意义吗?
So in UIKit a lot of things are marked public,
所以在UIKit很多东西都标记为公开,
All the things you can use have to be marked public cuz
您可以使用的一切必须标记为公开因为
it's in a different framework than your app,
它比你的应用在不同的框架,
Your app is kind of a framework, in a sense, so
你的应用程序是一种框架,在某种意义上,所以
that's public,
这是公共的,
And then, also notice farther down,
然后,还要注意进一步下降,
these methods are marked internal; that means I can
这些方法标记内部,这意味着我可以
only use them inside my framework, so I can't call any
只使用它们在我的框架,所以我不能调用任何
of these methods from Smashtag, they're internal,
Smashtag的这些方法,他们内部,
This actually, you haven't seen this keyword because
事实上,你没见过这个字,因为
it's the default, all the methods you've ever created
这是默认的,所有你曾经创建的方法
that you didn't mark private or fileprivate are internal,
马克,你没有私人或fileprivate内部,
It's the default, so
这是默认的,所以
you haven't put the word internal there, okay,
你还没有把这个词内部,好吧,
So, let's look at the public API,
所以,让我们来看看公共API,
Let's not even pay any attention to that, and
我们甚至没有注意,和
look at the public API,
看公共API,
This public API of Request, for making requests,
这种公共API的请求,发出请求,
we're only going to use three things,
我们只会使用三件事,
One is this convenience initializer
这是一个方便的初始化器
where you just give it something to search for and
你只是给它一些搜索
how many results you want,
有多少你想要的结果,
And then this method fetchTweets where you just
然后该方法fetchTweets你而已
give it this closure which it will call when it's done,
给它这个闭包,它将调用完成后,
It's gonna go off and do it on another thread and
它会去和在另一个线程
when it's done it will call,
当它结束的时候,它将调用,
And that's going to have an array of the tweets it found
这将有一个数组的tweet
that match your search,
匹配你的搜索,
what we're gonna use is this one down here, newer where if
我们将要使用的是下面这个,更新如果
And then last,
然后,最后
you ask it a request, give me a newer request,
你问它请求,给我一个更新的要求,
It'll give your request that you can use to get newer
它会给你的请求,您可以使用它们来得到更新
tweets,
微博,
Tweets that have been tweeted after
推特,推特
the previous one that you've got,
你的前一个,
So, that's all we're gonna use here,
所以,我们要在这里使用,
We're not really gonna use any of the other API
我们不使用任何其他的API
in this request,
在这个请求,
In your homework, you'll have to know this API here of
在你的作业,你必须知道这个API
Tweet cause you'll have to be able to get the text and
推特让你得能和的文本
the user information and also MediaItems so
用户信息和MediaItems
you can get the URLs of images that are in there, etc,
你可以得到图像的url,等,
But you never have to look at the private implementation of
但是你从来没有看私人的实现
this framework so don't even waste your time looking there,
这个框架所以不浪费你的时间,
Just look at things marked public,
看看事情标记为公开,
there's not a lot of things marked public- that's the only
没有很多事情标记为公开——这是唯一的
thing you're going to look for,
你要找,
Now how do I use this framework,
现在我该如何使用这个框架,
this Twitter framework in Smashtag?
这个Twitter Smashtag框架?
Well, you have to do one step,
好吧,你要做的一步,
You can't just put them in the same workspace and
你不能只是把它们放在同一个工作区和
start working,
开始工作,
Well, two steps, one is I need to say import Twitter,
两个步骤,一个是我需要进口推特说,
Just like I say import UIKit, if I want to use this Twitter
进口UIKit就像我说的,如果我想使用这个推特
framework up here I have to say import Twitter,
框架在这里我不得不说进口推特,
That's gonna cause this tweet to start being
这微博开始的原因
recognized as a type because it's gonna see this
公认的一种类型,因为它会看到这个
tweet type right over here,
微博类型,
But the other important thing, don't forget,
但另一件重要的事情,不要忘记,
is you need to tell Xcode that when you build Smashtag that
你需要告诉Xcode,当你建立Smashtag呢
app includes Twitter in it,
应用包括推特,
And you do that by going to the Smashtag project, okay,
和你去看Smashtag项目,好吧,
the project settings,
项目设置,
And go all the way to the bottom where it says
,一直到下面说
Embedded Binaries,
嵌入二进制文件,
And just pick up the product of your Twitter framework,
就拿起你的Twitter的产品框架,
You see where it says Products right here?
你看到它说产品呢?
Just pick that up and drag it in here, and that says,
刚接,并将其拖在这里,说,
please put Twitter framework into my Smashtag,
请把到我Smashtag Twitter框架,
because my Smashtag uses it,
因为我的Smashtag使用它,
If you don't do this step, then it'll all compile but
如果你不做这一步,那么它会编译不过
then when Smashtag runs, Twitter won't be there, and
当Smashtag运行时,Twitter不会,
so it will fail,
所以它将会失败,
Now, I'm gonna make you do that step as part of
现在,我要让你做这一步的
your homework,
你的家庭作业,
I will post this code for Smashtag, but
我将这段代码Smashtag,但是
I'm not gonna post the workspace, so
我不会把工作空间
you're gonna have to build the workspace on your own,
你必须建立自己的工作区,
All right, so let's continue,
好吧,让我们继续,
Now that we've got this array of tweets,
现在我们有这个数组的tweet,
what are we gonna do with this array of tweets?
我们要怎么处理这个数组的推文?
Let's start by doing a fetch for our search text,
我们先来做一个获取搜索文本,
So we got our search text,
我们有我们的搜索文本,
we wanna go fetch all those things on there,
我们想去获取所有这些事情,
That's what we're supposed to do in search for tweets,
这就是我们应该做在搜索微博,
Let's make another function here,
让我们做另一个函数,
another little private func,
另一个小私有函数,
I'm gonna call it twitterRequest,
我要叫它twitterRequest,
which is gonna return a Twitter,Request,
它会返回一个Twitter,请求,
But yeah, here's another thing,
但,是的,这是另一件事,
This I can call tweet because I'm importing this Twitter
这个我可以叫推特,因为我进口Twitter
framework and there's no other class called tweet, so
框架和没有其他的类称为tweet,
i just have to call it tweet,
我只需要称之为微博,
Its full name is actually Twitter,Tweet,
它的全名是推特,推特,
Just like, you know, UITableViewController,
就像,你知道,UITableViewController,
it's full name is UIKit,UITableViewController,
它的全称是UIKit UITableViewController,
use Twitter,Tweet because I think in Assignment 5, you
使用推特,推特,因为我认为在赋值5,你
Now i'm gonna
现在我要
might end up wanting to have you own local tweet class,
可能会想有你自己的地方推类,
So I'm gonna use Twitter,Tweet and
所以我要使用推特,推特
Twitter,Request everywhere but I wouldn't have to as long as
Twitter,请求无处不在但我不会只要
I didn't have a class called Tweet or Request otherwise,
我没有一个类称为Tweet或者请求,否则,
But this is a pretty generic name request so putting
但这是一个非常通用的名称请求把
the Twitter dot on front might be kind of a good idea anyway,
Twitter点面前可能是一个好主意,
All right so
好
the Twitter,Request function here is just going to return
Twitter,请求函数就会返回
a Twitter request that matches this search text,
一个Twitter请求匹配该搜索文本,
And that's really, really simple,
这是真的,真的很简单,
I'm just gonna say, if I can let the query for
我只是想说,如果我能让查询
the search term equal the search text,
搜索词等于搜索文本,
And I wanna make sure that that query is not empty,
我想确保查询并不是空的,
So I don't wanna search for nil or for the empty string,
所以我不想寻找零或为空字符串,
So I'm just keeping that out of it right here,
我只是保持在这里,
And otherwise I'm just gonna return a Twitter request using
,否则我要返回一个Twitter请求使用
that convenient initializer I told you about called Search,
方便我跟你说过初始化称为搜索,
And I'm just gonna pass that query and,
和我要通过查询,
well let's get 100 of them,
我们得到100,
Okay, so we're gonna, we'll grab 100 tweets at a time,
好的,所以我们会,我们会抓住一次100条,
And if that's not true, if the search term is nil or
如果这不是真的,如果零或搜索词
it's empty, then I'm gonna return nil from this,
它是空的,然后我将返回nil,
So let's make this be, you know, optional,
所以让我们做这个,你知道,可选的,
Okay, so everyone understand what this function does?
好的,所以大家都理解这个函数到底做了些什么?
It just makes a Twitter request that will search for
它只是让一个Twitter搜索请求
our searchText, that's all it does,
我们searchText,,
So now down here in searchForTweets,
所以现在在searchForTweets下面,
I can say if I can let request equal the twitterRequest,
我只能说如果我能等于twitterRequest让请求,
which hopefully it can make,
希望它能使,
Okay, now I have a request,
好了,现在我有一个请求,
Now I just need to cause that request to happen,
现在我只需要使该请求发生时,
So I'm just gonna say this Twitter request,fetchTweets,
所以我想说这个Twitter请求,fetchTweets,
So this fetchTweets function right there, you see it?
这fetchTweets函数,你看到了吗?
The top one, okay,
上面的,
it takes this closure right here as an argument,
它以这个闭包作为参数,
I'm gonna double click on it, to show what it does here,
我要双击它,给它,
I'm going to use trailing closure syntax to get rid of
我将使用后关闭摆脱语法
the parentheses there,
括号,
Now what's this?
现在这是什么?
This is the only argument in my closure,
这是唯一的论点在我关闭,
Those are the tweets that it fetched,
这些微博获取,
See it's an array of tweets,
看到微博的一个数组,
I'll call this newTweets,
我叫newTweets,
Okay, so that's going to be an array of tweets,
好了,这就是一个tweet数组,
I don't even need the parentheses here by the way,
我甚至不需要括号在这里顺便说一下,
So I have newTweets,
所以我有newTweets,
So newTweets is gonna be an array of Tweet that it
所以newTweets会推它的数组
fetched; now, of course,
获取;现在,当然,
it's doing this off the main queue, right?
这样做主要的队列,对吧?
It's gotta go do that Twitter request,
这是要去干,Twitter的要求,
what if it's a really slow network?
如果它真的是一个缓慢的网络呢?
Or Twitter is really slow that time or whatever,
或Twitter是很慢,时间等等,
I finally got these new tweets back, what do I wanna do?
我终于这些新推回来,我想做什么?
So inside here,
所以在这里,
Well I just want to add them on to the end of my model,
我只是想将它们添加到我的模型,
Here's my model, it's an array of array of tweets,
这是我的模型,它是一个数组,数组的微博,
right?
对吧?
Here's an array, so I'm just going to take my model, and
这是一个数组,所以我要把我的模型,和
append onto it this array of tweets,
添加到这个数组的tweet,
And actually, I'm not gonna append it on the end because
实际上,我不会添加结束,因为
I want all my new tweets to show up at the beginning,
我想让我的新微博出现在一开始,
so in section zero at the beginning, so
所以部分零开始
I'm gonna insert these new tweets at 0 in my array,
我要插入这些新微博(0)我的数组,
So right at the top,
所以正确的顶部,
So my new tweets are gonna come in at the top,
我的新微博要进来,
Make sense?
有意义吗?
Now, we have an error there,
现在,我们有一个错误,
Can anyone guess why this error is here before I
谁能猜出这个错误在这里在我吗
open it?
打开它吗?
>> Mutating,
> >变异,
>> What? >> Yeah, mutating,
> >什么?
>> Mutating,
> >变异,
That's a good guess but no,
这是一个很好的猜测,但没有,
It's because self, it's the old closure cycle problem,
这是因为自我,这是旧的闭合循环的问题,
right?
对吧?
Since we're accessing self here,
因为我们这里访问的自我,
these tweets as part of our self,
这些tweet作为自我的一部分,
We need to explicitly say that so
我们需要显式地说
that we can notice, we might have a memory cycle,
我们可以注意到,我们可能有一个记忆周期,
And do we have a memory cycle here?
我们这里有一个记忆周期吗?
In fact we do,
事实上,我们做的,
Because what if this view controller goes off to
因为如果这个视图控制器熄灭
fetch some tweets and it takes forever,
获取一些推特,要花很多时间,
And so the person says, I'll search for something else,
人说,我将寻找别的东西,
Now they said the search text is on the else and
现在他们说,搜索文本和其他
another fetch goes off,
另一个拿了,
And now here comes the first fetch and it's irrelevant now
现在来了第一个获取和现在无关紧要了
because I already looked for something else,
因为我已经找别的东西,
So we do here, want to be careful to ignore
所以我们所做的,要小心,不容忽视
this when it comes back and we also, if someone searches and
这个时候我们还,如果有人搜索和
it's taking forever and they hit back, we want our view
永远和他们予以回击,我们希望我们的观点
controllers to be able to leave memory as well,
控制器能够留下记忆,
So we don't want the closure, the cycle here,
所以我们不希望关闭,这里的周期,
we don't want this closure holding our self in memory,
我们不希望这个闭包在内存中保留自我,
So we don't want this to be a strong pointer and
所以我们不希望这是一个强指针
we need to check to make sure that when we get back,
我们需要检查以确保当我们回来时,
it's still what we're interested in,
它仍然是我们感兴趣的,
So how can we break this cycle?
所以我们怎样才能打破这个循环?
We're just gonna use our friend weak self, okay?
我们要用我们的朋友弱自我,明白吗?
That's easy,
这很简单,
And that turns this into an optional,
把这变成一个可选的,
So we added a question mark,
我们添加了一个问号,
Boom, we broke that cycle,
繁荣,我们打破这个循环,
So even if this fetch is sitting out there fetching,
所以即使这种获取是坐在那里获取,
it's not gonna be keeping our view controller in memory,
它不会让我们的视图控制器在内存中,
Our view control can leave memory, and
我们认为控制可以把内存和
if it comes back and
如果它回来
it's gone, then this line of code will not execute,
它走了,然后这行代码不会执行,
How about dealing with the fact that our request might
如何处理我们的请求可能吗
have changed?
已经改变了吗?
Well, to do that,
嗯,要做到这一点,
I'm gonna have to keep track of our lastTwitterRequest,
我要跟踪lastTwitterRequest,
actually we've got to put it inside here,
我们必须把它在这里,
Okay, I'm gonna keep track of it, and
好的,我会跟踪它,
then in here I'm not going to do this unless our
在这里我不打算这样做,除非我们
request equals the lastTwitterRequest,
请求= lastTwitterRequest,
So if this request that came back is not the last one we
如果这个要求不是我们最后一个回来
issued, then I'm not gonna do it,
发布了,那么我不会这样做,
And so let me go up here and
所以我来这里
say private var lastTwitterRequest and
说私人var lastTwitterRequest和
that's going to be a Twitter,Request of course,
这就是Twitter,请求当然,
Request, optional, is not always set,
请求,可选的,并不总是集,
Everyone kinda see what I'm doing there?
每个人都看到我在做什么吗?
And of course this is saying self again, so we'll put self
当然这是说自己,所以我们会把自我
in there and of course self is weak so we'll do that,
当然,自我是弱所以我们会这样做,
So that's all good,
这就是好,
Any other problems you can see with this?
任何其他问题你可以看到吗?
I don't see any so far,
我没有看到任何迄今为止,
So it's all good, So,
所以这都是好的,所以,
before we go hooking up our table view,
在我们去勾搭表视图,
let's just make sure that our Twitter fetches are working,
我们确保我们的Twitter获取工作,
And I'm gonna do that by putting a didSet
我要用一个didSet
up here on my model, and every time my model changes,
在我的模型,每一次我的模型变化,
I'm just gonna print the tweets out,
我要打印消息,
Now luckily I've made it so
幸运的是我做了
the tweet is CustomStringConvertible,
CustomStringConvertible推特,
it implements description,
它实现了描述,
It can print itself as a string so
它可以打印作为字符串
this is an array of those,
这是一个数组,
So this will print out an array, actually an array
实际上这将会打印出一个数组,数组
of an array of this tweet printed out as a string,
数组的tweet打印出来作为一个字符串,
So we're just gonna print it out there,
所以我们要打印出来,
Just seems like it should work?
只是似乎应该工作吗?
Let's go give it a try and find out,
让我们去试一试,找到答案,
We'll do this on iPhone 7,
我们将做这个在iPhone上7,
Pay attention right now because this
注意现在因为这个
is not in fact going to work,
不去工作,
And this won't work for you either and you're gonna need
这也不会为你工作,你需要
to do a couple of things to make a Twitter fetch work,
要做的几件事情让一个Twitter获取工作,
By the way you see we have these prototype cells that
顺便说一下你看到我们有这些原型细胞
have to have reuse identifiers; gotta remember to
需要重用标识符;要记住吗
fix that later,
解决这个问题后,
Alright, so we run, and look at this thing it puts up here,
好的,我们跑,看看这个东西了,
Smashtag would like to access Twitter accounts,
Smashtag想访问Twitter账户,
So you're not allowed to write an app that just starts
所以你不可以编写一个应用程序,只是开始
posting things for people on Twitter behind the scenes,
在Twitter上发布的东西的人在幕后,
Okay, when you write an app it is always going to ask,
好的,当你写一个应用程序总是要问,
the first time you try to use Twitter, whether it's allowed,
你第一次尝试使用Twitter,不管它是允许的,
So I'll click okay, and let's go look in our console and
所以我点击好了,让我们去看看我们的控制台
see if it printed,
是否打印,
It didn't, all it printed out here is, couldn't discover
它没有,它打印出来是,无法发现
Twitter account type, hm, why would it say that?
Twitter帐户类型,嗯,为什么它会这样说?
Well, that's because your simulator, it's just a device,
嗯,那是因为你的模拟器,它只是一个装置,
it needs to have Twitter, a Twitter account, basically,
它需要有推特,一个Twitter账号,基本上,
your device needs a Twitter account, so
你的设备需要一个Twitter账号,所以
where do we set that?
我们在哪里集合?
So let's go back to our simulator,
让我们回到我们的模拟器,
here it is, I'm gonna go hardware, home button, okay,
在这里,我要硬件、家庭按钮,好吧,
you can also do command, shift, F,
你也可以命令,转变,F,
Is hardware home button,
是硬件按钮,
And I'm gonna go over to the Settings app on my simulator,
和我要去设置应用程序在我的模拟器,
But you can do it on your device as well,
但是你可以在你的设备,
And if you go down in settings, here's Twitter,
如果你去设置,这是Twitter,
Look at that,
看,
Twitter right there,
推特,
And here's where you type in your
这是你输入你的地方
Twitter username and password,
Twitter用户名和密码,
And if you don't type this in,
如果你不类型的,
then no apps on your system can access Twitter,
然后应用程序在您的系统上无法访问Twitter,
Cuz how would they- they'd have to know who you are,
因为他们会如何——他们必须知道你是谁,
So I'm gonna type this here, I'm gonna do it off screen cuz
所以我要类型在这里,因为我要做掉屏幕
I don't want you to see my password,
我不想让你看到我的密码,
So now I am logged in on Twitter,
所以现在我在Twitter上登录,
So now if I go back and start my app
所以现在如果我回去并开始应用
It will both be in allowed because I clicked OK,
它都将被允许因为我点击OK,
And I'll be logged in so
我将登录
it'll have an actual Twitter user that can do it,
它将有一个实际的Twitter用户,可以这样做,
And sure enough, look down here at the bottom,
果然,看下面的底部,
We're getting all kinds of tweets being printed out here,
我们得到各种各样的推文被打印出来,
So here's a tweet,
这是一条微博,
Here's its unique ID,
这是其惟一的ID,
Here's the person who tweeted it,
这是在推特上它的人,
Here's when it was tweeted,
这是推的时候,
Here is the text of the tweet,
这是推特的文本,
This one's got an embedded URL, etc,
这一个有一个嵌入式URL等等,
So we're doing well,
所以我们做的很好,
We've got our tweets coming in,
我们有我们的微博,
So now all we need to do is load them up into our
现在我们需要做的就是它们加载到我们
table view,
表视图,
So what do we need to do to load this thing up in
我们需要加载这个东西
the table view?
表视图?
Now, surprisingly simple actually, the two pieces we
现在,令人惊讶的是简单的实际,我们两块
have to do, one is every time we change our model we have
每次都要做的,一个是我们改变我们的模型
to tell the table view that it changed and then we have
告诉表视图,然后我们有改变
to implement those table view data source methods,
要实现这些数据源表视图方法,
So let's start with the first one,
让我们从第一个开始,
Actually we have already changed our model once,
实际上我们已经改变了我们的模型,
Right here, we changed our model and
在这里,我们改变了我们的模型
we told the table view about it, so that's good,
我们对表格视图,这样很好,
Here we're changing our model,
这里我们改变我们的模型,
So we need to tell the table view about it,
所以我们需要告诉表视图,
So self?,tableView,
表视图,自我?
And what did I do here to my model?
这里我做了什么我的模型吗?
I just inserted a section at the beginning,
在一开始,我只是插入一段
So there happens to be a tableView method called
这恰好是一个视图方法调用
insertSection,
And it just says, you inserted some sections,
它只是说,你插入的部分,
Which ones?
哪一个?
ask you about those and put the rows in there for you,
问你关于这些,把行给你,
I will go and
我将去
And this sections is an index set,
这部分是一个索引集,
which you can give it an array literal,
你可以给它一个数组文字,
So I just inserted section zero,
所以我就插入部分零,
So I'll just put an array with just zero in it,
所以我就把数组只有零,
And I'm gonna use the fade animation
我要使用渐变动画
to show that fading in,
表明,衰落,
So, insertSections,
所以,insertSections,
So, this is me telling the tableView, I changed my model,
这是我告诉tableView,我改变了我的模型,
so ask me again,
所以再次问我,
Ask me those tableView data source,
问我这些tableView数据源,
Now, since I told it exactly what I did it's only gonna ask
现在,既然我告诉它我也只是要问什么
me about that section, which is nice, higher performance,
部分的我,很好,更高的性能,
Then reloadData, the hammer reloadData,
然后reloadData,锤子reloadData,
in which case it would ask me for all rows in all sections
在这种情况下,它会问我所有部分的所有行
again; so here I know exactly what I did,
再次,所以我知道我所做的,
Now this actually is dangerous code here,
这实际上是危险的代码,
This is really easy to add this line of code and
这是很容易添加这行代码
now your app just acts weird,
现在应用程序行为怪异,
It just acts weird all the time,
它行为怪异,
Can anyone, want, guess why this
谁能想,猜一猜为什么
adding this line of code would cause my app to go all weird?
添加这行代码会导致我的程序去所有奇怪的吗?
It's because this is a UI call,
这是因为这是一个用户界面,
And what queue are we on here?
我们和队列在这里吗?
Some queue, not the main queue,
一些队列,而不是主要的队列,
Whatever queue we fetched those tweets on, okay?
我们无论队列获取这些tweet,好吗?
So we're not on the main queue,
所以我们不是主要的队列,
So we can't make a UI call here,
所以我们不能在这里打个UI,
Right, so we have to dispatch this back to the main queue,
对的,所以我们必须派遣这回到主队列,
So this is something that,
所以这是,
will just take some getting used to for
只是需要一些时间来适应吗
you guys with this multithreading,
你们用这个多线程,
cuz you're gonna do these things in this other queue,
因为你会做这些事情在这其他队列,
and you're gonna update your table view, and then
你要更新你的表视图,然后
it's like what's going on my app is just acting so strange,
就像发生了什么在我的应用程序只是真是奇怪,
And that's why- because you can do
这就是为什么——因为你可以做
UI stuff on the main queue,
UI主要队列上的东西,
And it's not gonna warn you or necessarily crash,
这并不是要警告你或必然崩溃,
it might eventually crash, it's just gonna act all weird,
它可能最终崩溃,它只是将所有奇怪的行为,
So, fixed that,
所以,固定,
This is good,
这很好,
We've got the table view updating our model and we've
我们有更新我们的模型,我们的表视图
got the table view knowing about change to the model,
有表格视图了解变化模型,
So now all we need to do is implement this
现在我们需要做的就是实现这个
UITableViewDataSource protocol so
所以需要协议
that it can get the data from us,
它可以从我们获得的数据,
So let's do it,
让我们来做,
Number of sections, how many sections are in our table?
数量的部分,我们的表中有多少部分?
Anyone know?
有人知道吗?
Yeah,
是的,
Exactly, candy thrown at you cuz that's exactly right,
没错,糖果扔在你因为这是完全正确的,
tweets,count,
推特、数
It's just the number of arrays that we have in our model here
只是数组的数量,我们已经在我们的模型中
because each of this arrays inside here are a section, so
因为这个数组里面的每一个部分,所以
perfect,
完美的,
And then what about this one?
然后这个呢?
Here we're being asked how many rows are there in tweets
我们被要求在微博有多少行
subsection?
分段吗?
That's just count also,
这只是数也,
So we've designed our data structure so
所以我们设计的数据结构
that these are super easy to implement,
这些是超级容易实现,
which I highly recommend if you can do it,
我强烈建议,如果你能做到,
You can't always do it,
你不能总是这样做,
But if you can it's nice,
但如果你能很高兴,
So now a little more difficult, only a little
所以现在更困难,只有一点点
though, is cellForRowAt index path right here,
不过,cellForRowAt索引路径,
So here's where we have to return the UITableViewCell
所以在这里我们必须返回UITableViewCell
that we're gonna use to draw,
我们要用来画画,
Now, let's go back to our Storyboard here and
现在,让我们回到我们的故事板在这里
let's just start out with something simple,
让我们从一些简单的开始,
Let's try using here a subtitle cell,
我们试着用一个副标题细胞,
So I'm gonna click on this cell,
所以我要点击这个单元格,
And will change its style from being custom
并将改变其风格定制
to being subtitle,
副标题,
So there's title and subtitle,
这是标题和副标题,
And I'm gonna set the title to be the text with the tweet,
我要将标题设置为文本与推特,
And I'm gonna set the subtitle
我要设置字幕
to be the person who tweeted it,
在推特上它的人,
So let's try that and see how that looks,
让我们试试,看看看,
So how am I gonna do that?
所以我要怎么做呢?
Two things I need to do here,
我需要做两件事,
One is I need to dequeue a reusable cell, and
一个是我需要出列一个可重用的细胞,和
I to tell iOS which prototype to use,
我告诉iOS使用哪一个原型,
which prototype in the Storyboard,
在故事板的原型,
So lets go back to our Storyboard,
我们回到我们的故事板,
And I only have one prototype,
我只有一个原型,
It's this one,
这是这一个,
That's the one I wanna use,
这是一个我想使用,
So I need to give it an identifier,
所以我需要给它一个标识符,
I'm gonna call it Tweet,
我要叫它推特,
because that's what this cell shows,
因为这是这个单元格显示,
It shows a tweet,
它显示了一个微博,
Notice that caused my warning to go away,
请注意,导致我的警告消失,
Because all these prototype cells
因为所有这些原型细胞
always need an identifier,
总是需要一个标识符,
And now when I go back here,
现在,当我回到这里的时候,
I can change this from reuseIdentifier to Tweet,
我可以改变这个从reuseIdentifier到微博,
Okay, so now, I am able to dequeueReusableCell
好的,现在,我能够dequeueReusableCell
that will be a copy of that prototype that's subtitled,
那将是一份字幕的原型,
So all my rows are gonna be subtitle rows,
所以我所有的行要字幕行,
So now I've got this cell,
现在我有这个细胞,
it's of type UITableViewCell by the way,
这类型的UITableViewCell顺便说一下,
since it's a standard type not a custom type,
因为它是一个标准的类型不是一个自定义类型,
How do I configure it?
我怎么配置?
Well, for me to configure the cells, to set the title and
嗯,对我来说,配置细胞,设置标题和
I need to know which Tweet it's asking me for here,
我需要知道哪些推这里问我了,
the subtitle,
副标题,
And I know which Tweet it's asking because it's
我知道这微博问,因为它是
saying cellForRowAt,
说cellForRowAt,
This is the row that's the tweet that is asking
这是一行的推特问
me to give it a UITableViewCell for,
我给它一个UITableViewCell,
So I'm gonna let tweet equal
所以我要让推特相等
my model sub indexPath,section and
和我的模型子indexPath,部分
indexPath,row,
indexPath、行
So I'm just getting this row in this section,
所以我刚刚这一行在本节中,
this gets the first array, the section,
这第一个数组,部分,
I'm just getting the row out of it,
我刚刚的行,
So now I got the tweet, so now I can just update the cell
现在我有了推特,所以现在我可以更新细胞
really easily, cell,textLabel,
真的很容易,细胞,textLabel,
It might be an optional ?,text equals,
它可能是一个可选的吗?
let's have that be the tweet's text,
让我们成为推特的文本,
This is something that you'll see in here, we go to
这是你会看到在这里,我们去
the Twitter, and look for the Twitter framework at Tweet,
Twitter,寻找Twitter框架在推特,
and you'll see that the very first one in fact, is text,
,你就会看到,第一个事实上,是文本,
And then we'll make this cell detailTextLabel,
然后我们会让这个细胞detailTextLabel,
its text will be the tweet's user's name, let's say,
它的文本将tweet的用户的名字,比方说,
So again, Tweet, user, username,
所以,微博、用户、用户名、
So, that's why I'm getting that information,
所以,这就是为什么我得到这些信息,
Do you understand that?
你明白吗?
Part of it, okay?
它的一部分,好吗?
So, that I'll came out of this Tweet,
所以,我会走出这个微博,
This is of type Tweet,
这是类型的推特,
Everybody got that?
大家都明白了吗?
All right, so is that it?
好了,是吗?
Do we need to do anything else to hook this thing up and
我们需要钩这个东西和做别的吗
make it work?
让它工作吗?
Turns out no,
原来没有,
So let's just run,
让我们来运行,
Okay, there it is,
好吧,在这里,
The world's greatest Twitter client,
世界上最伟大的Twitter客户端,
Look at that,
看,
It looks beautiful,
它看起来很漂亮,
No, of course, in fact,
不,当然,事实上,
this is the world's ugliest Twitter client right here,
这是世界上最丑的Twitter客户端,
But it is working,
但这是工作,
These are tweets,
这些都是微博,
But anyway, you can see here's the tweets and
但无论如何,你可以看到这里的tweet
here are the person who tweeted it,
这是在推特上它的人,
Now obviously, this is awful UI,
现在很明显,这是可怕的UI,
Just absolutely horrendous UI,
是绝对可怕的UI,
You would never have a Twitter client like this,
你永远不会有这样的Twitter客户端,
We want our UI in these cells to look much nicer,
我们希望我们的UI在这些细胞看起来好得多,
much more customized to a tweet,
更多定制的一条微博,
So we're gonna go back to our Storyboard here,
所以我们要回到我们这里的故事板,
And instead of using this awful subtitle style cell,
而不是使用这个可怕的字幕样式细胞,
we're gonna build a custom cell,
我们将构建一个定制的细胞,
And this custom cell is gonna have more good looking and
这个定制的细胞会有更多好看
more of the data that comes with a Tweet,
更多的数据,有一条微博,
So let's just build it,
让我们建立它,
Let's go here and make this a little bigger, make some room,
我们走吧,让这大一点,做一些房间,
All right, I'm gonna grab some labels out of here,
好了,我要抓住一些标签,
There's a label, this will maybe be,
有一个标签,这也许会,
let's say this is the Tweeter,
假设这是推特,
This is the person who's doing the Tweet,
这是做微博的人,
By the way, this is a case where we're showing user
顺便说一下,这是一个情况我们显示用户
content really,
内容真的,
These tweets are content,
这些微博内容,
They're not like the title of a button or something,
他们不喜欢一个按钮的标题,
it's actually the content that the user has requested to see,
它实际上是用户请求的内容看,
So I'm gonna use a font here,
我将使用一个字体,
You see this font?
你看到这个字体吗?
I'm not gonna use the system font,
我不会使用这个系统字体,
I'm going to go down and start using this text styles,
我要下来,开始使用这个文本样式,
So the Tweeter is going to be at the top,
推特是在顶部,
I'm gonna have that be a headline font,
我要有标题的字体,
So this is gonna be the headline font and
这是标题的字体和
this could change over time, okay, whatever the system
这可能随时间变化,无论系统
thinks headline font is and it'll be true in every app,
认为标题字体是真的,它会在每一个应用程序,
The headline will always be using this font in every app
标题总是会使用这种字体在每一个应用程序
and users could even go into settings and
甚至用户可以进入设置和
change the size of their fonts,
改变字体的大小,
If they're like me and
如果他们喜欢我
they're visions going they can set them bigger,
他们想象他们可以设置更大,
And the fonts will get bigger automatically so
和字体将自动变大
ther's big advantage to using these font styles,
其他的一大优势,使用这些字体样式,
So there's that one,
所以有这个,
There is the text of the tweet itself, so
微博本身的文本,所以
we'll just call that text,
我们只是打电话,发短信,
maybe a good font is body font because this is really, this
也许一个好的字体是身体字体因为这是真的,这一点
For this one,
为了这一个,
is the heart of what we're doing here, this body thing,
是我们所做的核心,这个身体的事情,
One thing that's kinda cool with UILabel, the text
一件事与UILabel有点酷,文本
in the tweet is probably gonna be multiple lines, and
微博可能会多行,和
it's gonna wrap,
它会包装,
When you have a UI label like that,
当你有一个UI这样的标签,
you wanna set this property lines to be zero,
你想要设置该属性为零,
If you have zero predefined lines then the UILabel
如果你有0然后UILabel预定义的行
will be however many lines it needs to be fit
然而将多行需要合适吗
the information with wrapping,
与包装的信息,
Whereas this one is line one this all one line,
而这一行一这一行,
And if it's too long it just gets dot dot dot at the end,
如果它太长就最后点点点,
all right?
好吧?
What else do I wanna do here?
我在这里想做什么?
Let's do another label here for
让我们做另一个标签
when the tweet was tweeted out, when it was created,
当推了推特,建立之时,
That one is probably something like a caption, we'll say,
一个可能是类似的标题,我们会说,
Small little text at the bottom,
小文本在底部,
We'll go ahead and center than right there,
我们将继续和中心,
Let's also get an image,
让我们也得到一个图片,
Let's go down and find the image view down here,
我们走下来,发现下面的图像视图,
Where is our image view?
我们的图像视图在哪里?
Here it is,
在这里,
Drag it out here, This is gonna be the profile
拖出来,这是要这个概要文件
image of the Tweeter,
推特的形象,
So whoever tweeted this will have their little image here,
这里谁会发他们的小图片,
This one, by the way,
这个,顺便说一下,
I don't know how big profile images are on Twitter,
我不知道大剖面图像在推特上,
And I don't care because I'm gonna make this thing
我不在乎,因为我要做这件事
always be a fixed size,
永远是一个固定的大小,
So how do we make an image like this be a fixed size
那么我们如何让这样的一个图像是一个固定大小的
using auto layout?
使用自动布局?
And it turns out what you do is you Ctrl+Drag to itself,
其实你要做的就是按Ctrl +拖,
And when you do,
当你做什么,
you'll see that you have the option to fix its width,
你会发现你可以选择修复它的宽度,
And you can Ctrl+Drag, and fix its height,
你可以按Ctrl +阻力,并修复它的高度,
You can also to both at the same time,
你也可以在同一时间,
And, so what width and height has it fixed it to?
,那么它固定宽度和高度了?
Well, we can look over here in the size inspector,
我们可以看这里尺寸检查器,
and see that it's fixed it to 71 by 67,
看到它的固定到71年到67年,
That doesn't sound very computer science-y,
这听上去并不太计算机科学,
I'm gonna fix it to 64 by 64,
我将修复它到64年到64年,
So I've made it so
所以我做了
this image view is always gonna be 64 by 64,
这个图像视图总是会64年到64年,
I don't care how big the person's actual profile image
我不在乎的人多大的实际轮廓图像
is, I always want it to be that way,
是,我总是想要这样,
Okay, so there's another little auto layout
好的,还有一个小自动布局
tidbit for you,
为你的花絮,
speaking of auto layouts, I need to lay this stuff out,
说到汽车布局,我需要把这些东西,
All right, so
好吧,那么
I kinda want it to look, eh, something like this,
我有点想要看,呃,是这样的,
See what I mean?
明白我的意思吗?
Approximately, and so I'm just gonna use stack view,
约,所以我要使用堆栈视图,
So we'll stack those two things together, like that,
所以我们将这两件事堆在一起,这样,
Look at our things here, fill and fill,
看看我们这里的东西,填补和充实,
That's perfectly fine,
这是非常好,
Let's go over here,
我们去这里,
Let's stack those together,
让我们堆在一起,
That's fill and fill,
填补和充实,
One thing about these two, by the way, they're gonna be
关于这两个,顺便说一下,他们会
sharing the space in this stack view equally,
共享空间在这个堆栈视图一样,
But I don't want them sharing equally,
但我不想让他们分享同样的,
I actually want the text to get more of this space,
我真正想要的文本来获得更多的空间,
So I'm gonna click on the Tweeter,
所以我要点击推特,
And I'm gonna go over to this size inspector,
我要去这个尺寸检查器,
And I'm gonna do something cool,
我要做一些很酷,
which is set its content hugging priority,
这是拥抱的优先级设置其内容,
I'm gonna set its vertical content
我要设置它的垂直内容
hugging priority to be higher than the other one,
拥抱的优先级高于另一个,
So they're both 251,
所以他们都是251,
You see, that one's 251, that one's 251,
你看,一个是251,这是251年,
So I'm gonna set this one to be 300,
所以我要设置为300,
just anything higher than 251,
任何高于251,
And that means that when the space is being allocated
这意味着当被分配的空间
between this tweeter and
这个推特和
the text, it's gonna hug the tweeter's content,
的文本,它会拥抱推特的内容,
And the text is gonna get all the rest,
和休息,会得到所有的文本
So that's a way that you can kinda,
这是一种你可以有点,
when you're sharing space between two things,
当你两件事情之间共享空间,
All right, so now let's put these two in a stack,
好了,现在让我们把这些堆栈,一分之二
Maybe we'll put some spacing here, something like that,
也许我们会放一些间隔,这样,
Alignment here, top is good, I want them both at the top,
对齐,顶部是好的,我希望他们两个在顶部,
I think that's good, lined up at the top,
我认为很好,排列在顶部,
If I like that and fill is fine, I've got this,
如果我喜欢,并填写好,我有这个,
Now I'm gonna do the same thing we did before,
现在我要做同样的事情,我们之前做的
which is I'm gonna put this in the corner,
这是我要把这个在角落里,
And I'm gonna Ctrl drag to the top,
我要Ctrl拖到顶部,
I'm gonna Ctrl drag to the leading edge,
我要Ctrl拖前缘,
I'm gonna Ctrl drag to the trailing edge,
我要Ctrl拖后缘,
And I'm gonna Ctrl drag to the bottom edge,
我要按Ctrl拖动底部边缘,
So I want that out there,
所以我希望,,
And again, the same thing,
再一次,同样的事情,
I'm gonna take this and change it to standard if I can,
我要把这个标准如果我可以改变它,
I can't, so we'll go 0,
我不能,所以我们就去0,
And same thing here,
这里也一样,
Standard if I can, can't, we'll do 0,
标准如果我能不能,我们会做0,
So I've made this stock view that contains all
所以我做了这个视图包含所有股票
the stuff fit in there,
适合的东西,
So I basically done the auto layout necessary to make this
所以我基本上做必要的自动布局
thing use the space properly,
正确地使用空间,
And I can still change the size of the cell, all right?
我仍然可以改变细胞的大小,对吧?
I can click on it and I can make it a little bit smaller
我可以点击它,我可以让它小一点
and all that stuff is going to, you know,
和所有这些东西,你知道,
stick to the edges, so that'll be fine,
坚持边,这样会很好,
Now, this is great,
现在,这是伟大的,
in fact if we go back to our table view controller and
事实上如果我们回到我们的表格视图控制器
if I comment out this cell configuration because we don't
如果我这个单元配置,因为我们不发表评论
have a subtitle so these don't make any sense any more,
有一个副标题这没有任何意义,
And we run, then we gonna see that our UI hopefully,
然后我们跑,我们会看到,我们的UI希望
if we didn't forget anything,
如果我们什么都没忘记,
It's going to look in some ways a little better,
它看起来在某些方面好一点,
Yeah, so it kinda looks better,
是的,所以它看起来更好,
Now, the only thing that's not better is we lost our data
现在,这不是更好的唯一的事就是我们失去了我们的数据
because I commented out the data loading right here,
因为我注释掉数据加载,
So this is what we want UI to look like basically with
这是我们想要的样子基本上的UI
an image here and that there,
一个完整,
But we need to set all this data,
但是我们需要所有这些数据集,
So how do we that?
那么我们如何?
Since this is a custom cell over here,
因为这是一个定制的细胞,
We have to do with a custom subclass
我们要做一个定制的子类
of this UI table view cell right here,
这个UI的表视图单元格,
So, I'm gonna create one of those, New File,
所以,我将创建一个新文件,
Let's go here and New File,
我们去这里,新文件,
Again, Cocoa Touch Class; this time though,
再次,可可触摸类;这一次,
it's not a TableViewController it's a TableViewCell,
TableViewCell,它不是一个表
I'm gonna call it TweetTableViewCell cuz
我要叫它TweetTableViewCell因为
it shows the tweet,
它显示了微博,
put in the same place as all the rest of my stuff there,
放在同一个地方我所有剩下的东西,
Here's my table table view cell, it gives me awakeFromNib
这是我的表的表视图单元,它给了我awakeFromNib
which is kinda nice but I don't need it and setSelected
挺不错,但我不需要,setSelected吗
I don't do anything special when my table view cell is
我不做任何特殊的当我的表视图单元格
selected but I could, I could draw a blue background or
选择但我可以,我可以画一个蓝色的背景或
something like that if I wanted, but I don't,
类似的,如果我想要,但我不,
So, I have this TableViewCell subclass,
所以,我有这个TableViewCell子类,
I'm gonna go back to my Storyboard and
我要回到我的故事板
make sure that I set the identity,
确保我的身份,
don't forget this step,
别忘了这一步,
Set the identity to be a TweetTableViewCell,
设置身份TweetTableViewCell,
If you forget this step,
如果你忘了这一步,
you won't be able to do any outlets or anything like that,
你不能做任何媒体或类似的东西,
Now, I wanna wire outlets up to this new class I
现在,我想线媒体这个新类
just created, so I need to get them both on screen,
刚刚创建的,所以我需要让他们两个在屏幕上,
I'll show you kind of a cool way to do that,
我将向您展示一种很酷的方式,
Let's get the assistant editor up here,
让我们的助理编辑,
remember I could do manual, blah, blah, blah,
记得我可以做手册,等等,等等,
but another way is to hold down the option key, and
但另一种方法是按住option键,和
just click on the thing that you want to be on the right,
点击你想要的东西在右边,
I think I showed this before, but option
我认为我给这个,但选项
clicking in the navigator will put that thing on the right,
点击在右边的导航器将那件事,
All right so let's move this over more, some space there,
好吧让我们移动这个多,一些空间,
All right, so I need to wire up outlets to these four
好了,所以我需要这四个连接插座
things, right, the tweet or the text or the image,
事情,推特或文本或图像,
So let's just do that,
让我们来做,
We'll go here, Ctrl+drag,
我们就去这里,Ctrl +拖,
screen out, I'll call this my tweet, what did I call this,
屏幕,我称之为我的推特,我称之为什么了,
my tweetProfileImageView,
我的tweetProfileImageView,
Cuz it's gonna be a UIImageView that shows
因为它会UIImageView显示
the Tweeter's profile,
推特的形象,
Let's do the little create down here,
下面让我们做小创造,
Ctrl+Drag, from that,
Ctrl +拖,,
We'll call that tweetCreatedLabel,
我们称之为tweetCreatedLabel,
To label it,
标签,
Shows when it was created; let's do out little tweeter
显示创建的时候,让我们做小的推特
right here and we call that our tweetUserLabel,
在这里,我们称之为tweetUserLabel
this is gonna show the label of the tweet
这是要给微博的标签
user and then we have the text right here that's gonna show
用户然后我们有在这里会显示的文本
the actual tweetText, tweetTextLabel,
实际tweetText tweetTextLabel,
So I've got these nice little outlets right here,
所以我有这些漂亮的小网点,
Now of course I need to be able to set these outlets with
当然我需要能够设置这些网点
something and here's where I need public API in my
的东西,在这里我需要在我的公共API
table view cell, that gives me the data I need to do that,
给我数据的表视图单元格,我需要这样做,
And I'm just going to have my public API be tweet,
和我要我的公共API是推特,
give me the Twitter,Tweet that you want and
给我推特,推特,你想
I'll load these babies up,
我将加载这些婴儿,
That's what it's saying here,
这是说,
Of course we need to import Twitter,
当然我们需要导入Twitter,
Cuz we're using it in this class,
因为我们在课上使用它,
And when you set this Tweet I'm just going to on didSet,
当你设置这个微博我要didSet,
Update my UI just like I was a controller but
更新我的用户界面就像我是一个控制器
I'm not, I'm not a controller, I'm a view actually,
我不是,我不是一个控制器,实际上我是一个视图,
It's the only time a view can have these outlets,
这是唯一一次一个视图可以有这些媒体,
So I need some private func to do that updateUI,
所以我需要一些私人func updateUI,
Now, time is running a little bit short here, so
现在,时间有点短,所以
I'm just going to type this in real quick
我要在快速类型
I believe I have tweet cell,
我相信我有推特细胞,
There it is, okay?
在这里,好吗?
But you can look at this later,
但是你可以看看这个之后,
But I'm just basically setting all the outlets here,
但我基本上设置这里所有的媒体,
See how I'm just setting these outlets like setting the tweet
看到我只是设置微博这样的设置这些媒体
label, text to be the tweet's text,
推特的文本标签、文本,
setting the user label to be the user description,
设置用户标签用户描述,
Notice by the way I'm blocking the main thread here,
顺便通知我阻塞主线程,
If this was my homework, bam I just got dinged,
如果这是我的作业,我刚升到的bam,
So make sure you fix this, okay?
所以一定要解决这个问题,好吗?
If you're gonna use my code in any way in your homework,
如果你要在你的作业中使用我的代码以任何方式,
which you probably want to,
你可能会想,
then you're gonna wanna fix this,
然后你要想解决这个问题,
Don't do this on the main thread,
在主线程不这样做,
Don't block the main thread,
不要阻塞主线程,
But, does anyone understand what updateUI is doing here?
但是,有人理解updateUI是什么做的吗?
It's just taking this Tweet that I was giving,
它只是把这个微博,我是给予,
and loading this up,
和加载,
And this is happening over and over for
这是反复发生
every row in the table that gets displayed,
显示表中的每一行,
This is happening, the copy of this class has been made and
这正在发生,这个类已经和副本
this is happening,
这正在发生,
Now, how do we set this?
现在,我们如何设置?
We set this back over here and our TweetTableViewController,
我们在这里设回TweetTableViewController,
In the same place that we configured the cell here for
在同一个地方,我们配置了细胞在这里
the subtitle one,
副标题,
And in fact, I still need the tweet, but I don't need that,
事实上,我仍然需要推特,但我不需要,
I'll leave those there, so
我将离开这些,所以
you can remember that code when you look at it later,
你可以记住代码当你看它之后,
But instead of setting those things, I just want
而设置的这些东西,我只是希望
to set that tweet, I wanna set this var right here,
设置微博,我想这里的var,
But for me to set the var right here,
但对我来说设置var在这里,
I need to get my table view to be one of these,
我需要让我的表视图是其中一个,
So, I need to use an as,
所以,我需要使用一个,
So, I'm gonna say,
所以,我想说,
if I can let the tweetCell equal the cell,
如果我能让tweetCell等于细胞,
this reusable cell that I got, as a TweetTableViewCell,
这是我得到的可重用的细胞,作为TweetTableViewCell,
then, I can say, cell set your tweet to be my tweet,
然后,我可以说,细胞设置你的微博我的微博,
That goes in this row, section, and row,
进入这一行,部分,行,
Now, we set the, what, sorry, tweetCell,tweet,
现在,我们设置了,,对不起,tweetCell,推特,
We set the class of these, of this prototype right here,
我们设置的类,这个原型,
the prototype for this cell,
这个细胞的原型,
We set it with the identity
我们把它与身份
inspector to be a TweetTableViewCell,
检查员TweetTableViewCell,
So, when we come in here, it will, in fact,
所以,当我们在这里,,事实上,
this as will work,
这是工作,
Okay, it will be a TweetTableViewCell cuz we said
好的,这将是一个TweetTableViewCell因为我们说
that in the Storyboard, so, it created that kind of thing,
在故事板,所以,它创造了这样的事情,
all right?
好吧?
So, let see if this works,
让我们看看这工作,
Okay, it is working,
好吧,这是工作,
Look, we've got the time the person tweeted this,
看,我们有时间发的人,
it's got the person who tweeted it,
有推特的人,
it's got the text of the tweeting, but we get no image,
它有推特的文本,但我们没有图片,
Why didn't we get people's images here?
为什么没有得到人们的图片吗?
Okay, why do you think we didn't get these,
好吧,你为什么认为我们没有得到这些,
these images?
这些图片吗?
Well, let's go look at our console,
好吧,让我们去看看我们的控制台,
What does it say?
它说什么了?
No!
不!
App Transport Security,
应用交通安全,
You recognize that from last time?
从上次你意识到吗?
It's because these profiles are http something not
这是因为这些概要文件的http
https something,
https的东西,
So, we know how to fix that,
因此,我们知道如何解决这个问题,
We'll just go back to Info,plist right here,
我们就回信息,这里的plist,
And add a row for App Transport Security,
应用交通安全添加一行,
We'll open that up, we'll add Arbitrary Loads here,
我们将敞开大门,我们将添加任意加载,
we'll make that be, yes, we allow arbitrary loads,
我们将是,是的,我们允许任意加载,
There's another problem here though,
不过,这里还有一个问题
Look at all these tweets,
看看这些微博,
Look how they're cut off, you see?
看他们是如何切断,你看到了吗?
Every row is the same size and it's not big enough for
每一行是相同的大小和它不是足够大
most of the tweets,
大多数的微博,
It's just dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, dot,
它只是点,点,点,点,点,点,
Wouldn't it be cool if these rows could be different sizes
不是很酷,如果这些行可以大小不同
depending on how big the tweet is?
根据推特是多大?
Well, of course we can do that,
当然我们能做到这一点,
Let's do it,
让我们做它,
Let's go see how this size is being said right now,
让我们去看看这个尺寸现在被说,
Right now, it's being said, if we go and
现在,它是说,如果我们去
inspect this cell in its size inspector, look,
检查这个细胞的尺寸检查器,看,
the row height is 96, so, every single row is 96,
行高度为96,所以,每一行是96,
What we wanna do is in our viewDidLoad right here,
我们要做的是在我们viewDidLoad在这里,
we wanna say that our tableView's row height is not
我们想说,我们的表视图的行高
96, it's UITableViewAutomaticDimension,
96年,UITableViewAutomaticDimension,
But as I said before, we also want to give it a little help
但正如我之前所说的,我们也想给它一点帮助
by setting its estimated row height to something,
通过设置其估计的行高,
And I'll tell you what,
我会告诉你,
let's set it to what's in the Storyboard,
让我们把它在故事板中,
tableView,rowHeight, okay?
tableView rowHeight,好吗?
So, I'm getting the rowHeight out of the Storyboard,
所以,我得到了rowHeight故事板的,
using it as the estimate,
使用它作为估计,
And then, I'm resetting
然后,我重置
the rowHeight to be the AutomaticDimension,
的rowHeight AutomaticDimension,
And sure enough, see, look,
果然,看,看,
this tall tweet is getting extra space and
这个高推获得额外的空间
some of the smaller tweets, I don't know if we have any,
一些规模较小的微博,我不知道我们有什么,
you can probably see it if we go like this,
你可以看到它如果我们像这样,
The smaller tweets get less space, okay?
较小的微博让更少的空间,好吗?
So, that's good,
所以,这很好,
We're out of time, so, if you have to go, feel free,
我们没时间了,所以,如果你有去,感觉自由,
The last thing I'm gonna do here in a little over time is
我要做的最后一件事就是在多一点时间
add a text field at the top that lets us type in what
添加一个文本字段中,让我们在什么类型
we wanna search for instead of always looking for Stanford,
我们想要寻找,而不是一直在寻找斯坦福大学,
So, we're gonna get Stanford out of there, okay?
我们会得到斯坦福出来,好吗?
So, how do we do that?
那么,我们如何做呢?
It's real easy,
这是真正的简单,
We have, if you remember,
如果你还记得,
the table view, it's got this little header view at the top,
表视图,它有这个小标题视图在顶部,
So, I'm just gonna take a UITextField,
所以,我只是需要一个UITextField,
Remember this editable text field we learned about in
记住我们学过的可编辑的文本字段
the last lecture?
上节课吗?
And I'm gonna put it on the top,
我要把它放在顶部,
It's a little hard, sometimes, to see where it's going,
这有点困难,有时候,看到它,
but when it looks like this, the width of the table, then,
但当它是这样的,桌子的宽度,然后,
you've got it, it's dropping it in there,
你得到了它,把它,
It's also a little hard to select and click on,
这也是一个很难选择和点击,
So, you're gonna wanna use that Ctrl + Shift + Click,
所以,你要想用Ctrl + Shift +点击,
And that way, you can pick either the controller, or
这样,你可以选择控制器,或
the table view, or in this case, the text field,
表视图,或在这种情况下,文本字段,
I'm gonna inspect it and change it a little bit,
我将检查它,改变它,
I'm just gonna make the font a little bit bigger,
我要让字体大一点,
we'll say 22,
我们会说22日
Now, notice I can also set all those text field things I was
现在,请注意我也可以设置所有这些文本字段
talking about,
说什么,
Like, I don't want it auto-correcting,
我不想让它自动更正,
I don't wanna say, search for hashtag SuperBowl and
我不想说,搜索标签超级碗
change it hashtag SuperSpaceBowl, okay?
改变标签SuperSpaceBowl,好吗?
So, I don't want any correction going on,
所以,我不希望任何校正,
Keyboard type, ooh, look,
键盘类型:哦,看,
there's a Twitter keyboard type,
有一个Twitter键盘类型,
It's probably got # and @ sign, things like that,
它可能有#和@符号,类似这样的事情,
The return key,
返回键,
that's just the key on the things says return,
这是关键的事情上说,
I'm searching here, so, I wanted to say search,
我在这里搜索,所以,我想说搜索,
So, that means the return keys gonna say, I'd search,
所以,这意味着返回键会说,我搜索,
Also, a little clear button would be cool,
一个清晰的按钮很酷,
button you can press the clear out what's going on,
按钮可以按下清除发生了什么,
So, you can kinda configure this in any way you want
所以,你可以配置在任何你想要的方式
to make it work in there,
让它在那里工作,
Now, normally I would run this and show you that it's there,
现在,我通常会运行这个和证明它的存在,
let's wire it up first, so, it actually does something,
我们先连接起来,因此,它实际上是什么,
but of course,
当然,
It's real easy to wire up a text field if you just
这是真的容易连接如果你只是一个文本字段
wanna hook it up to an outlet and set its delegate, and
要连接到一个出口并设置其委托,和
then, you can find out when the return key is pressed,
然后,您可以找到返回键被按下时,
So, let's do that,
所以,让我们这样做,
We'll go here, let's get our TweetTableViewController on
我们将在这里,让我们得到TweetTableViewController
screen at the same time,
与此同时,屏幕
We just wanna create an outlet to that thing,
我们想创建一个出口的事情,
I'll put it, right in here,
我把它,就在这里,
So, I'm just,
所以,我只是
again, I will probably wanna Shift + Click to select it,
再一次,我可能会想Shift +单击以选中它,
I, oops, picked the wrong one,
哦,我选错了,
So, let's Shift + Click, click this, select this,
让我们Shift +单击,单击,选择这个,
and Ctrl + Drag from it, and see it's a UITextField, and
和Ctrl +拖动它,看到它是一个UITextField,和
I'm gonna call this my searchTextField,
我要叫它searchTextField,
Simple as that,
简单,
When it's set, I'm going to set myself as its delegates,
集的时候,我要自己设置为代表,
searchTextField,delegate = self,
searchTextField委托=自我,
Of course, for me to be its delegate, I have to go
当然,对我来说它的委托,我得走了
up here and say yes, I am a UITextFieldDelegate,
上面说,是的,我是UITextFieldDelegate,
Okay, they're all the methods are optional in there, so,
好吧,它们都是可选的方法,所以,
I have now successfully implemented that protocol,
我已经成功地实现了协议,
Ooh, what happened here?
哦,发生了什么?
Yes, okay, so that's so I've set the delegate,
是的,好吧,这就是我设置委托,
Now, I'm gonna implement the delegate method I want,
现在,我要实现我想要的委托方法,
which is that should return,
应该返回,
It get sent to me when the return button is sent,
它给我发送返回按钮时,
So that is textField,
这是文本框,
notice as I type textField it shows me them all,
注意到当我类型文本框它向我展示了他们所有人,
and it is this one right here textFieldShouldReturn,
这个textFieldShouldReturn,
Let me make this bigger, bigger so
让我把这个更大,更大的
you can see it better,
你可以看到它更好,
Okay, so here should return,
好吧,这里应该返回,
If I get return, I'm actually gonna check to make
如果我得到回报,我要检查
sure I'm getting this from my searchTextField,
从我的searchTextField确定我得到这个,
because someday I might have other text fields and I wanna
因为有一天我可能会有其他的文本字段,我想
make sure I'm getting, I know which one I'm talking about,
确保我得到,我知道我说的是哪一个,
So textField is this argument right here, and
文本框是这个论点,
I'm just checking to make sure it's me,
我只是检查,以确保它是我,
And if that is true then I'm just gonna set my
如果这是真的,那么我就会把我
searchText = searchTextFields,text, okay?
searchText = searchTextFields文本?
Makes sense and when I set my searchText,
是有意义的,当我把searchText,
that's immediately going to start it going,
马上要启动它,
Notice that ShouldReturn also returns a Bool which is
也注意到ShouldReturn返回一个布尔值
whether to do what it normally does when return is pressed,
是否要做什么它通常按下返回时,
Which in this case is nothing,
在这种情况下,是什么,
cuz we don't have any target action or
因为我们没有任何行动或目标
anything else, but we'll return true,
别的,但我们会返回true,
Sure do what you normally do, now the only other thing
确定做你通常做的事情,现在唯一的另一件事
here is now that we have the searchTextField,
这是现在我们已经searchTextField,
up here when we set our searchText,
当我们设置searchText,
We wanna update our searchTextField,
我们想要更新searchTextField,
And I'll be careful here in case I'm doing it in prepare,
我会小心,以防我在准备,
We'll set it to the searchText that we just set it to,
我们将它设置为searchText,我们只是把它
Also I'm going to have my searchTextField
我要还我的searchTextField
resignFirstResponder here,
resignFirstResponder这里,
That's if somebody types something and hits go search,
如果有人的类型,点击搜索,
and we search for something and put it in there,
我们寻找的东西,把它放在那里,
I'm gonna take the keyboard away,
我要拿走键盘,
Cuz I just don't wanna have the keyboard blocking
因为我不想有键盘挡住
the results that they just asked for,
他们只是要求的结果,
And also someone sets it in code,
也有人在代码中设置了它,
I'm gonna get rid of keyboard,
我要摆脱键盘,
Someone might be in the middle of typing but
有人可能在打字但
if someone sets it in code rather than typing,
如果有人在代码中设置了它而不是打字,
Let's get that keyboard out of the way, all right?
让我们键盘的,对吧?
So let's go do that,
让我们去做,
Leave this code on the screen so you can see it,
离开这段代码在屏幕上你可以看到它,
All right, so here is our text field, it's kinda of hard to
好的,这里是我们的文本字段,它有点难
see under this carrier, we'll fix that in a second,
看到在这个载体,我们会解决这个问题,
Let's go and search for #stanford again,
让我们去寻找#斯坦福大学,
Oops, I'm not gonna do this, watch this,
哦,我不会这样做,看这个,
Okay that looked easy to type, didn't it?
好吧,看起来容易类型,不是吗?
Well let's go here and
我们去这里
say Keyboard, turn off the hardware keyboard,
说键盘,关闭硬件键盘,
Now when we click in here,
现在,当我们点击在这里,
ooh, it's a lot harder to type,
哦,这是一个很难类型,
#stanford, okay so now you're getting into what
#斯坦福大学,所以现在你进入
I'm saying about learn to type like your users will be,
我说的关于学会喜欢你的用户将类型,
So here I'm going to search, goes in stanford and
这里我要搜索,斯坦福大学
search for it,
寻找它,
Let's go and search for something else here,
让我们去寻找别的东西,
Maybe we'll search for,
也许我们会寻找,
this is kind of dangerous because people might say, but
这是危险的,因为人们可能会说,但是
Trump >> Okay,
特朗普> >好的,
there's some Trump ones,
有一些胜过的,
Now, we've done all this,
现在,我们所做的这一切,
I wanna fix this thing though,
我想解决这个事情,
where this looks really bad at the top here,
这看起来很糟糕的顶部,
And there's this really easy fix to that,
这很容易解决,
Which is I'm just going to, this is the fix,
我要,这是修复,
The fix is everything in the UI as you've learned,
解决办法是在UI中,你学到的一切,
I'm just gonna embed this in a navigation controller,
我要嵌入在导航控制器,
Okay, when you embed this in a navigation controller and run,
好的,当你嵌入这个导航控制器和运行,
you can see that it makes a nice title at the top,
你可以看到,这是一个很好的标题,
it moves the text field down,
它移动文本框,
it's just much nicer all around,
只是好得多,
Okay, see how it has done that from a bit down here,
好吧,看看它所做的,从下面一点,
One other thing I'm gonna do is put placeholder text in
另一件事我要做的是把占位符文本
there, I meant to show you that,
我想告诉你,,
Sorry, let's do that, if I go back to here click this,
对不起,我们这样做,如果我回到这里点击这个,
That thing in here, swipe this guide,
那件事在这里,刷本指南,
You can put a placeholder text like this, Twitter Search and
你可以把这样的一个占位符文本,Twitter搜索和
see it shows it in there, kinda like gray,
看到它显示它,有点像灰色,
So that when you run, it's more obvious to the user,
所以当您运行,用户更明显,
what is that big white space, all right?
这是什么白色的大空间,对吧?
Be clear to them that it's a Twitter search,
是很清楚,这是一个Twitter搜索,
You know all you need to know to do your homework,
你知道所有你需要知道的做你的家庭作业,
Good luck with it,
祝你好运,
>> For more, please visit us at Stanford,edu,
> >更多内容,请访问我们的斯坦福大学edu,